Previously on "Marvel's Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
Daisy's powers are the missing key
manipulating e Gravitonium.
I wouldn't have done any of this
if I didn't believe it was going to work.
I'll never forgive you.
You had a psychic split.
But that dark persona, that's not you.
I really don't know where we go from here.
You're standing next to the man responsible for shooting Talbot.
Daisy Johnson shot Talbot.
That was an android.
Come with me.
Let me show you what we are really up against.
My vantage point is much higher than yours.
I come with you, my people get away unharmed.
I can agree to that.
I see they've shown you to your new accommodations.
Of all the blindfolds I've forcibly worn,
that was one of the nicest.
There's a method to this madness.
All of your questions will be answered in the morning.
Not my first rodeo, so I may have already figured out
a little bit of what's going on here.
You've got the Gravitonium
and the total disregard for human safety.
Check.
You've got Ivan Drago and Crusher Creel on the payroll.
And then there's you, rogue general,
operating with zero oversight.
Add it all up,
it just doesn't feel like an Air Force operation.
It's not.
It's Hydra.
I thought we stomped you out.
Yes.
Just as you were stomped out.
And yet here we are in the same room.
I'd like to tell you my story,
and I think you'll know it's time.
Time for what?
It's time for S.H.I.E.L.D. and Hydra to finally unite.
Good morning.
Rise and seize the future.
One more day. Are you excited?
Excited to be done with these lectures.
Can't stand another one of these old dudes
droning on about placement.
Well, at least today's guest speaker is cool.
You know, I heard ‭that he once used alien DNA
to actually reverse the body's aging process.
Oh, shut up, Sitwell.
You're just jealous.
Of you being a teacher's pet?
They've got you better trained than any of our mutts.
You're jealous ‭because I am going places
while you will be stuck in middle management.
Calm down.
Take a seat.
I know everyone is excited about graduation tomorrow.
As a reminder, there will be a final examination tonight.
And now, here to speak to you
about another post-grad opportunity,
please welcome Daniel Whitehall.
Good morning.
It's an honor to speak with you,
the future of our organization.
Tomorrow, you will leave these halls
and venture out into society.
And though you may be behind the scenes,
there are many ways that you can help Hydra
dismantle the oppressive state.
Since World War II and the success of Steve Rogers,
there have been many failed attempts
to create a super soldier.
But after some ungainly setbacks...
we're close --
close to creating the most powerful man on Earth.
Now, this is the particle infusion chamber,
an apparatus that can force human cells
to take on the properties of a raw material.
Imagine...
a man with the density of lead, with the volatility of cesium.
The possibilities are endless.
Can someone name another substance suitable for infusion?
Yes, Mr. Von Strucker.
Why not use Red Skull's Tesseract?
It's the greatest power source we've ever had.
Intriguing.
Looking to our past for inspiration.
That's a waste of time.
There's no way that we could take it from S.H.I.E.L.D. unnoticed.
We would blow our cover.
Well, I suppose you have a better substance in mind?
We're not gonna find it by digging up our history.
Instead, we should look to where the Tesseract came from
to find new materials.
Meaning?
Outer space.
Finally!
Some forward thinking.
You're going to S.H.I.E.L.D.,
admin division.
I-Isn't that what you wanted?
You okay?
That test was tough for everyone.
I'm fine.
Hear about your placement yet?
Nothing.
Getting anxious.
Well, I would be, too.
Especially if I picked a fight with Strucker.
You know that he put those two up to that.
Doesn't matter.
You punched the future leader of Hydra in the face.
You screwed your chances of getting a good placement, genius.
Ms. Hale.
Daniel Whitehall ‭would like a word with you.
You've made quite the impression lately.
Seems you're one of the few females to make it to commencement.
It's a tough school.
And you completed your final test?
Well-done.
It's a rite of passage.
You must eliminate any weakness,
no matter how difficult.
I imagine it wasn't easy to sleep last night.
Not with all the boys sobbing through the walls.
Leadership expected nothing less.
In fact, we're confident
we see the future of Hydra in you.
That's why I've selected you for my program.
Sir. I'm honored.
I've dreamed of working with you,
and I really think that the chamber can revolution--
No, no, no.
Von Strucker will be working on the chamber.
I-is this because he and I got into a fight?
In a sense, yes.
We're actually impressed by your strength, your mettle.
We think ‭that you will be essential
in engineering the perfect human specimen for the chamber.
But... sir, I'm -- I'm not a biologist.
Correct, but you're the only candidate left with the other...
necessary qualifications.
You want me to be --
Artificially inseminated.
It's quite exciting, yes?
You should be honored.
You will give birth to our new leader.
As I said...
we see the future of Hydra in you.
What about my future?
As requested, you'll be placed
deep undercover ‭within the Air Force, perhaps...
you'll even become an astronaut.
However, once the seed has been perfected,
we expect you'll serve the cause.
Sir...
I'm flattered...
but is there an option where I utilize my talents elsewhere?
You always have a choice whether or not to comply.
Hail Hydra.
That's what I thought.
Good morning.
Rise and seize the future.
Poor boys could never keep up.
Well, her weaknesses are more glaring than you think.
She doesn't look weak to me.
Any idea ‭what leadership has planned for her after graduation?
Oh, they have yet to decide.
What's to decide?
Whitehall designed her to lead.
Whitehall is dead.
So, does he know ‭where I'm gonna be assigned after graduation?
It's being discussed.
He knows ‭that you're top of the class.
Runs in the family.
You don't think they're gonna stick me somewhere boring
- like Air Force, do you? ‭- Hey, hold on.
I happen to think that Air Force is very good placement.
You get to see combat, flight training.
You could even become an astronaut.
That's why I joined.
An astronaut?
Why didn't you ever tell me?
That would've been so cool.
You would've been like 10 times cooler.
Maybe.
But I wouldn't have had you.
Let me guess.
Your country calls.
Sorry, sweetie.
We've got a problem.
Is this an Air Force matter?
S.H.I.E.L.D. captured Gideon Malick.
Is he talking?
It's bad. We have to move fast.
Here.
I need you to take this,
locate the device ‭that's hidden in my vault,
find somewhere safe.
You're now ‭overseeing communications.
Fisher.
Fisher, what is this? Look at me!
What the hell is going on?
Okay, after New York, we found transceivers
in the wreckage ‭of one of the Chitauri cruisers.
We reached out. Someone answered.
You made contact with aliens.
It's an alliance of several races.
They call themselves the Confederacy.
Well, why the hell ‭wasn't I brought in on this?
General?
Gonna need you to come with me.
Come on, Hale.
Step away.
This is for your own safety.
Hail Hydra!
Get him!
Fool! Get him to medical now!
How could you let that happen?!
Now! Move!
I was looking forward to making that traitor talk.
You all right?
Yeah, fine. I just...
I thought we'd seen the last of Hydra.
Well, don't worry.
After today,
you'll never have to see one of those squids again.
I don't understand
what my dog has to do with me graduating.
Your attachment to that mutt is a liability.
You cannot serve until you complete the test.
I'm the only one left!
You're seriously gonna stop me from serving
because of some barbaric ritual?!
Do not question the Hydra way!
- You trust in the system! - Why not?!
Look where it's gotten us!
We're this close to being wiped out!
All the more reason to devote yourself now.
Eliminate your weakness.
Wake up!
Me obeying you -- that is weakness!
You, with your blind faith, with this stupid tradition --
that's weakness!
No!
It is a rite of passage to a life built on control and survival!
That's why, when you cut off the head,
two more spring up!
And now we're the last two.
General Talbot?
Your family's here to see you.
Okay.
Not a train, because the last one was a train.
Choo-choo. Choo-choo train.
Right? Uh...
Strawberry? It's not a strawberry.
It's a cat.
Nice job, Dad. You're on a roll.
Hey, we can do this,
because I got a mind like a steel trap.
We can get through this.
All right, so, last one's a train.
Wait. I don't understand.
He was getting better,
and now you want to transfer him somewhere...
More comprehensive.
But he's getting better. He's calm.
Today's a good day, Mrs. Talbot,
but the damage to his frontal lobe is severe.
It's gonna take a lot more time to retrain his brain
to control his impulses and think clearly.
No! No!
That's not a friggin' cat!
- That's not a cat! - Glenn, honey.
- Mom... - Honey, everything is okay.
George is just trying to help.
No, he showed me this -- this --
This is a tiger!
I said it was a cat, and he said it was right,
but I'm not right! I'm wrong!
How am I gonna get better if nobody's honest with me?!
Sir, take a moment and --
No, you take a moment! Stop it!
Stop pumping me full of that junk!
You s--
I...
I promise, we'll take very good care of him.
What in the Sam Hell...?
Hello?
Hello?!
Boy.
Stomach is so hungry, it's about to digest itself.
I still outrank you.
I don't know you.
You want to tell me
what we're doing in this godforsaken place?
Don't you walk away from me, young lady!
I don't appreciate being ignored!
You answer me!
You answer me before I rip those sorry little headphones
from your sorry little --
I see you've met my daughter, Ruby.
Cross-fit Tinker Bell is your daughter?
I've known you 20 years.
You never once mentioned having a child.
I never felt it was anything
you should be concerned with.
General Hale, where the hell am I?
All in due time.
You don't speak to your commanding officer like that.
You don't speak to a superior --
You don't speak to a superior officer like that,
and as such,
I'm ordering you to tell me exactly what's going on!
Because I'm not gonna put up with one more second of this --
Your Air Force career is over.
Your family is afraid of you.
And your lack of impulse control
is a threat to yourself and others.
Why are you telling me this?
Because there was a time in my life
when I felt like everything was out of control
and I needed a new purpose,
and I see you going through the same ordeal.
I think you and I can help each other.
How?
Let me show you what I'm working on.
I don't know what the hell this is.
I don't think she knows what the hell this is.
What the hell is this thing?
What the -- What is this thing?
What is this contraption?
To be honest, I have no idea.
They use it to move ships through the galaxies.
Galaxies?
You're suggesting --
Just let me explain.
After New York, my predecessors made contact
with life beyond the solar system.
They gave us this
to travel to the stars and meet with them.
Face to face.
I learned my predecessors hadn't just made contact.
They had struck a deal for protection.
From what?
The war coming to Earth.
It's only a matter of time before it reaches us.
This one's nuttier than a Butterfinger.
She just said what? War?
Why didn't this make it up through the chain of command?
How come it didn't get to me?
It's not Air Force, Glenn.
Then how did you get the project?
From General Fischer.
The day that he killed himself.
What flag do you fly, General Hale?
I think that's irrelevant when you're fighting a common enemy.
What flag...
do you fly?
Does it matter?
If you choose those squid billies,
it matters.
I didn't choose Hydra.
I was born into it.
Just like you were born and raised and indoctrinated
under the Stars and Stripes.
Indoctrinated? No. I wasn't.
I am not some wing nut,
and I stand by my red, white, and blue.
No. You stand by a country founded in oppression.
You stand by an eagle on a S.H.I.E.L.D.
even after you saw Daisy Johnson shot you in the head,
- point-blank. - That wasn't Daisy!
I know you think I've lost my onions,
but I've got a feeling it was one of Anton Ivanov's tin cans.
Am I wrong?
No, you're right. That was an LMD.
But it was created by S.H.I.E.L.D.,
and it was used on you.
Don't you see these symbols are irrelevant?
We are humans fighting for our survival.
We need every weapon we can get in this fight,
which is why I need you.
You filthy calamari Mata Hari.
Weapon?
What kind of weapon, exactly?
It's an old Hydra device.
I'm starting to understand why I might be here.
But you're not gonna get it from me.
'Cause I have a mind like a steel trap.
That's right.
I'm the one that hid the Hydra contraband.
And you want to know something else?
I'm not talking.
You got to let go of these old symbols.
You need to let go of the old Talbot.
I am giving you new purpose.
Help me save humanity.
I would rather die on my two legs
than slither on eight with you.
Actually, squids don't have legs.
They have tentacles.
They're cephalopods.
Let me out of here.
I swear, I will bust your kraken ass!
Let's try this conversation again
when you're feeling more reasonable.
You can't do this!
You let me out!
I'll never talk! You won't break me!
S.H.I.E.L.D.'s going to be coming through that door any day now!
You just wait and see!
Phil Coulson's coming for me!
Hello?
Is this supposed to keep me off-balance or something,
having me stumble out
to an Econo Lodge continental breakfast?
I give this place a C-minus.
Wait a minute.
"Oops! All Berries."
Okay. C-plus.
By the way, when Hale's done playing games,
I'll be in my room.
That girl, the member of your team I haven't met yet,
is she the one responsible for cutting my agent's arms off?
That's my daughter, Ruby.
Seems like a major strike against homeschooling.
She's not exactly helping your sales pitch
on the merits of teaming up with Hydra.
You're right.
Why don't you let me show you what I'm working on?
Bad idea.
You don't even know what it does.
I don't need to.
It's got that weird alien writing on the side.
Longitude.
Latitude.
And altitude.
You need to elevate your vantage point.
Would you grab that handle, please?
I'm good.
I've already been to space.
Pretty recently, actually.
No, you need to meet him for yourself.
Or what?
Why have you brought this human uninvited?
This is Phil Coulson.
He considers himself humanity's shield,
one of Earth's mightiest heroes.
Her words, not mine.
He's that ally that we need.
I'm hoping that you can show him the wisdom
of helping the Confederacy.
Very well.
Your world will soon become a battleground.
We will ensure humanity's survival.
For a price?
Much smaller than you'll pay if this comes to Earth.
So, the shadow guy will save humanity
from the alien warships.
Provided we meet certain terms.
Let me guess -- Gravitonium.
Amongst other things.
And Inhumans,
or engineered warriors, as they call them.
That's why you need me.
Yes.
You know where they are and how to contact them.
So you want my help to arm alien warlords.
You ever consider
they may not hold up their end of the bargain?
That maybe something called the Confederacy
will just enslave us all?
The thought has occurred to me.
Then, why cooperate with them? We need to fight back.
Finally, someone who gets it.
Altering the deal has always been my goal.
Now you see why we have to stop fighting each other.
And work together.
Right now, the Confederacy thinks
that we have no choice but to cooperate.
And you wanna prove we're not so easily coerced.
Not only that, but that we're a galactic superpower
not to be toyed with.
That's gonna require a significant display of force.
The whole "we will not go quietly into the night" bit.
What's your plan?
You're familiar with Dr. Whitehall?
I buried him.
Go, team.
We've been searching for an old Whitehall program.
It's a particle-infusion chamber.
It's designed to create the most powerful man.
Like Captain America.
Better than that.
Personally, I'd like to see the most powerful human
not be a man.
If the idea is to put your ninja daughter into that chamber,
this is gonna be a long conversation.
Cap was selected for his heart,
not cutting off hands.
Ruby is a perfect fit.
Her physical biometrics were optimized for particle infusion.
I'm sensing a "But."
She's not ready.
I'm not sure she has the temperament.
I'm wondering if your Daisy Johnson is a better fit.
You've made her into quite the formidable soldier.
"Made" is not the term I would use.
Well, as far as her heart is concerned,
I hear she sacrificed her own boyfriend
for the greater good.
Those decisions are not easily made.
- Now wait a minute - Look, she's powerful, she's intelligent,
she's calculating.
If the Confederacy needs Gravitonium...
Daisy Johnson is the one to deliver it.
By infusing her with Gravitonium?
Yes, she would have the power to level alien armies,
blow their ships apart.
She would be worthy of Whitehall's code name for the project --
Destroyer of Worlds.
Obviously, the guy was overcompensating for something,
- but - ‭No. No, stop.
This is a huge mistake --
a broken-planet-sized mistake.
Listen, my team wasn't hiding all these months.
We traveled to the future.
We saw the aftermath of that program.
You traveled to the future?
And back.
I saw the Earth cracked apart,
but not because of the Confederacy
or that alien ship.
It was because of my actions.
Exactly. Call off the search.
Do not let anyone enter that chamber.
Let me ask you something.
In this fever dream of yours,
are you the big, strong man
who's saving me from my mistakes?
- It's more complicated than that. You just - I'm sure it is.
I can't tell if you're delusional
or playing games with me.
This is very disappointing.
I thought you, of all people,
could see the bigger picture.
Clearly, you're just like the rest of them.
I listened to you! ‭Now listen to me, General!
I've heard enough.
Let's try this conversation again
when you're feeling more reasonable.
You're making a huge mistake!
No!
You have to listen to me!
It's cool.
Did you actually...
travel to the future?
'Cause my mom doesn't believe that.
Well-aware how crazy it sounds.
So, if you really did see the future, then...
tell me how I fail.
What do you mean?
You told my mom ‭that the Destroyer of Worlds
cracks the planet apart, so...
what did I do wrong?
I hate to burst ‭your apocalyptic bubble,
but it wasn't you.
Daisy Johnson.
Where is she?
That's a bad idea, Ruby.
You can't beat her.
Yes, I can.
Where is she?
I can't tell you.
But I can recommend some medication,
preferably at a high dosage.
Other than that, I'm not talking.
Why don't I show you how that worked out
for the last guy who said that to me.
Stay quiet.
Don't even make a sound. She'll --
Talbot.
What happened?
Phil?
‭I told them you would come.
I tried to hold out.
S.H.I.E.L.D. never came.
I'm sorry, Phil. I told them everything.
I held out as long as I could, but S.H.I.E.L.D. didn't show up.
I'm sorry.
Phil, Phil, it's --
Phil!
I'm sorry, Coulson! I'm sorry!
Daisy.
Daisy? Did you hear me?
Yeah, I heard you. I'm just thinking it through.
Strucker's escape, Anton, Creel...
And her connection to General Fischer.
Hale is Hydra.
Hale Hydra.
Seriously?
How are we still fighting Nazis today?
More importantly, ‭why does she need Coulson?
Okay. I don't even know where to start.
Obviously, ‭we have to get ahead of her,
but we have no leads,
because everyone in Hydra's locked up,
but we can't question them without false documents,
which I can't get without more resources.
So there's no -- ‭Hey.
Coulson chose you for a reason.
Take a breath.
This is just another fight.
No, it's not. I can't quake this away.
Remember combat training.
Take what you have,
use it to your advantage.
We have nothing.
We have a super villain.
Go on. Let's get it over with.
Tell her ‭I can't be trusted anymore.
You forget that I was Hydra in the Framework, too.
I know how this works.
I made decisions I regret.
This isn't the Framework.
And, truthfully...
...I don't regret it.
Just how it had to be done.
Well...
I'm not asking you to apologize for it.
I'm asking you to embrace it.
Okay.
Just need to calibrate the myoelectric interface.
Wouldn't want her suffering any neural distortion.
No disrespect, ‭but you sure you got this,
or do you need to consult Fitz?
No need.
Listen, I know you went into the Framework, but...
for those of us who were really plugged in, it was...
Well, it's hard to explain.
It...
It's you, but it's not you.
Look, I'm sorry. I'm -- I'm saying this all wrong.
- I understand. - ‭No, ‭what I mean is that,
it's not that Fitz ‭is still a bad guy out here.
It's that he was still a good guy in there.
Somehow.
I understand.
And thank you.
Okay.
Moment of truth.
So, when Yo-Yo wakes up,
she's gonna be stronger than before?
Theoretically.
Is something wrong?
Just that, lately,
she's been acting like she's bulletproof,
like nothing can stop her.
Well, that is not an uncommon attitude for our team.
No, this is different.
Yo-Yo saw herself in the Lighthouse,
so now she knows for a fact
that she lives far into the future.
So, if Yo-Yo subscribes to Fitz's theory
that time can't be changed, then --
She thinks she can't be killed.
Interesting.
What's your conclusion?
Well, we know that Hale went after Gravitonium,
so unless she's experimenting with artificial gravity,
I think ‭she's trying to build a weapon.
But why does Hale want Coulson?
I don't know.
If we can determine Hale's target,
then we can infer Coulson's role.
We have a lot of intel on file.
I just need a few hours' access
to the computers and the labs.
I can figure it out.
I can't help ‭when I'm locked up in this cell.
Not a chance.
I suspected you were listening.
Yeah, and, of course, your solution involves us letting you out.
- I'm only ‭trying to help, Daisy. - He's still on our side.
Don't defend him, not to me.
There's not a lot of team left here,
so let's hold it together.
We had to seal the rift shut.
By any means, no matter how sadistic.
- Okay. Well, would you have agreed to do it? - ‭Never.
Well, then, I didn't have a choice.
You didn't have a choice?
You drugged me, you restrained me,
and you cut into me.
I don't feel good about it, either,
but in a few hours,
the town up there would've been affected, as well,
so... I'm sorry.
I don't need your forgiveness.
I just need you to trust me.
You are not leaving this room.
You are Hydra.
Well, that's an advantage.
I salute the same flag as those people.
Yeah, but we don't turn on our own here.
Do you want me to recount all the times that you did?
We'll figure out another way to track Hale down.
- We've done it before. - And it was a trap.
It'll be different this time.
Yeah, 'cause you've got powers back,
and they've got the Gravitonium.
We already sealed one crack in the Earth.
It doesn't take a fortune teller
to see how easy it would be to make another one.
Are you listening to me?
Daisy!
Daisy, where are you going?
He's right.
It might not take a fortune teller,
but why not ask one anyway?
You want to bring Robin out of hiding
and risk her getting hurt?
Daisy...
Our leader is missing. We have to get him back.
We need every weapon we can get in this fight.
We'll return in a moment.
Again, I can't do anything
while I'm locked away in this dungeon.
Like a...
hideous, freckled stepchild.
Please.
You're not ‭in the least bit hideous.
Take it you and Daisy had a productive chat.
She quaked me against the wall and then stormed out,
so, yeah, ‭it was quite productive.
You've got that look.
I've been thinking about you and me --
about us.
Jemma.
Relax.
I know we get through this.
Do you recognize this?
Yeah. It's mine.
After my injury, I got the number engraved
because I couldn't remember the name.
See, that's the thing.
This one's yours.
That other tool belongs to Deke...
...who got it from his grandfather.
He's my...
...our...
...grandson?
Yeah.
But...
he's the worst.
I think he's perfect.
Plus, his very existence proves that
you and I make it to the Lighthouse...
and live long enough to raise a daughter.
Do you see what this means?
Yeah, I do.
It means that our daughter's obviously gonna marry
some belligerent space goon
if she's gonna give birth to a Deke.
No, Fitz.
It means you and I are invincible.