Previously on "Marvel's Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
We have to live with the choices we make.
And how I have to make mine.
Yo-Yo saw herself in the Lighthouse,
so she thinks she can't be killed.
You're our grandson.
His very existence proves that
you and I make it to the Lighthouse.
Do you see what this means?
It means you and I are invincible.
You cut into me.
You are not leaving this room.
I come with you, my people get away unharmed.
I can agree to that.
You want to bring Robin out of hiding
and risk her getting hurt?
Our leader is missing. We have to get him back.
Well, we know that Hale went after Gravitonium,
so I think she's trying to build a weapon.
It's a particle-infusion chamber.
If the idea is to put your ninja daughter into that,
this is gonna be a long conversation.
She's not ready.
I'm wondering if your Daisy Johnson is a better fit.
She would be worthy of Whitehall's code name for the project --
Destroyer of Worlds.
No. No, stop.
You're making a huge mistake!
No!
General Hale.
I know you're bummed the whole team-up thing
isn't gonna happen.
But it still seems kind of petty,
taking away my cot...
my chair...
and my Cap'n Crunch.
That last one really hurt.
And you're gonna destroy the Earth, so...
I told you we'd get Coulson.
And he'll pay for General Talbot
after he's turned over his Inhumans.
But for now...
I know you enjoy it,
the feel of a new material.
I've been looking forward to this one.
The question is, what do you want me to do with it?
Whitehall, Strucker, even Talbot --
they all wanted your compliance.
I'm offering transformation.
Into what?
A hero.
Show us what you can do.
Why hand him this?
Talbot already gave up the location of the chamber.
Yes, ‭and we're waiting for Strucker
to show us how to put it together.
His father never made it easy
for someone to steal his work.
- But Creel -- ‭- Creel will give us answers.
No one understood Gravitonium except for Ian Quinn,
and he's been in hiding for years.
But if Creel touches it --
Yes, he'll help us understand what we're dealing with here.
Before you give it to me.
I don't want to infuse your cells
with something we know nothing about.
So then why not talk to Coulson about it?
He has experience with it.
And I think after two days in isolation,
maybe an olive branch --
We've done the olive branch.
We stick the screws to him now.
A week without sleep and food,
we'll see what he has to say.
Let's begin.
Hey! Get me out!
Get me out of here!
Stop!
What happened?
What did you feel?
It's alive.
Wow. Hey, Simmons was right.
She said you might ‭become stronger than before,
but you're murdering that heavy bag.
Yeah.
Feels good to not be laying on a bed for once.
Yeah, well, maybe -- ‭Unh!
Maybe don't push too hard, though.
We just put those things on you.
I'm fine.
I'm just getting used to them.
Look, I know you like to do things fast,
but you don't know your strength yet.
So maybe a little caution couldn't hurt for a change.
‭I know that speech by heart.
Well, you're the one talking about how you're indestructible
and saying you can't die.
How was I supposed to take that?
I guess it was just, uh...
the pain medication talking.
Yeah.
Well, ‭you can at least hydrate.
Okay, Pacquiao?
And later on, I can run a diagnostic on those arms.
What? ‭Don't look at me like that.
What, I'm not babying you. I'm a mechanic.
A well-oiled machine needs oil.
Okay, yeah.
I don't see it.
None of you looks like me.
Well, I don't know ‭what to tell you, Grandpappy.
I guess your daughter found a real man.
Of all people.
Why couldn't it be Flint?
I liked Flint.
Well, that's a lovely sentiment.
That's almost as loving as when you had a robot...
point a gun to my head.
I didn't want to hurt anybody.
It's fine. It's the first move you made
that actually made me respect you a little bit.
It's my kind of move.
And this place, 80 years from now,
I'd survived on moves like that.
'Cause it was kill or be killed.
I know Johnson's still mad at me
about the whole "selling her into slavery" thing,
but you got to play the long game,
or else the whole world is gonna be a vacancy, right?
Maybe.
And you say ‭you don't see the resemblance?
Okay. Well, quality time was fun, but I'm late.
I don't know if you noticed, but...
ever since she's been in charge,
Daisy's kind of a hard-ass.
I noticed.
Can I pick your brain for a minute?
That's a weird saying.
I was hoping you could tell me more about our future.
I mean, you saw it -- it sucked.
No, I mean Fitz and me.
Do you recall any evidence of major injury,
any noticeable scarring, perhaps?
I don't remember you guys at all.
I didn't even know your real names.
Everyone in S.H.I.E.L.D. changed them
when they were getting hunted down.
I just knew you as Nana and Bobo.
But you guys ‭made it to the Lighthouse.
Good to hear.
Mom talked about you a lot
but never mentioned any health stuff.
I'm pretty sure you were tiptop.
You remind me of her.
If you want, I could tell you stories about what you --
I think it's best not to know too much.
It's enough to know Fitz and I live long enough to create her.
Yeah, well, you certainly will,
as long as you guys...
you know...
But anyway, I-I don't know how much longer I'm gonna make it
if I don't get a move on, because...
I don't know if you noticed,
but ever since she's been in charge,
Daisy has really just become a hard-ass.
I noticed.
You sure about this?
I understand the risk of taking her out of hiding,
but Robin is our best shot at finding Coulson.
I have to talk to her.
And look, I -- I get that you're afraid to see her again,
but she's ‭the most powerful tool we have.
She's just a kid.
Sorry I'm -- I'm late.
I was just -- just getting all my gear together,
but I'm ready to go. Geared up. Mission-ready.
I'll just go ahead and get to the command center.
- Was he late? - ‭I have no idea.
What's up?
I was hoping to have another word with you about Fitz.
We can't have that ‭conversation again, Simmons.
Yes, well, Robin may have answers,
but she may not,
whereas Fitz has a concrete lead on a Hydra weapon.
We get to that first, we get to Hale.
That could lead to Coulson and --
Fitz is sick.
You should be worried about that.
Look, you can compile his intel,
and we will review it when we get back.
But right now, Zephyr One is leaving.
And, Simmons, ‭Mack is in charge when I'm gone,
and he's under strict orders Fitz stays locked up.
Understood?
I understand what you're saying.
Good.
You might want to dial it back.
- I think she's wrong. - You made that perfectly clear.
But you're leading us now,
and it's new to everyone, not just you.
I'm just leading us to Coulson. Then he can have his job back.
Daisy won't listen. I think it's time we try a new approach.
To what? Why'd you drag me here?
Because I've realized we have to think differently.
Fitz started to, and he's paying for it.
But you can't deny it worked.
And you.
Mack said you believe you can't die.
I know it sounds crazy, Jemma --
I don't think it's crazy.
I believe it's true.
I'm glad someone understands.
I don't just mean you.
You guys didn't see yourselves in the future.
No. Deke is our proof.
His mother...
was our daughter.
- Deke... - Is our grandson.
I'm sorry.
- Thank you. ‭- No, no, ‭it's really quite sweet.
Well, it makes as much sense as anything else.
So we're ‭the invincible three, huh?
Now what?
Daisy's taking a long shot to find where Hale is keeping Coulson,
but we have something concrete
that can get us one step ahead of her.
That sounds good.
Hale may be after ‭a weapon powered by Gravitonium,
probably in a location
that Malick turned over to S.H.I.E.L.D.
That sounds bad. I'm in.
So we go to these places and knock down doors?
I can knock down doors now.
I can't go anywhere.
Fitz...
I know you feel like you're battling something inside you,
but I trust you.
Do you trust me?
Yeah.
Why?
Because I'm going to get you out.
And we're going to go after this thing.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Wait.
We have a problem.
Mack -- he's the only one that can open Fitz's cell now.
He won't want to, Jemma.
He'll stop us.
No.
He'll try.
It's far too powerful for you, for him.
Mr. Creel.
How are you feeling?
It won't leave my head.
Whatever's in there, I can't control it.
I think this is more about what's happening inside you.
What are you talking about?
You and I are a creation of the old Hydra.
That was destroyed.
When the thing we ‭identify with most falls apart,
we lose our footing.
We don't know what our next step is.
I didn't choose to be created by them.
But you get to choose now.
That's not what this feels like.
That's what you want.
We're going to conduct another test soon.
Whether you take that next step is up to you.
Watch your heads.
Just try to get comfortable, and...
we'll take off in a few minutes.
Thanks.
It's nice to see Mr. Fitz got you all back.
It's good to see you guys, too.
I-I'm -- I'm sorry ‭to take you out of hiding.
I wouldn't have done it if it wasn't...
really important.
Hi, Robin.
Let's get you into a seat, honey.
She hasn't been doing well --
for a couple weeks.
She isn't speaking to me.
She isn't drawing pictures.
I don't know what she's seeing.
Whatever it is, it's overwhelming her.
I understand that feeling.
Maybe I can find out what's on her mind.
Good.
Uh, take these to be translated.
I don't speak German.
Is something wrong?
Well, do these have ‭the answer we're looking for
or just more musings from a Hydra has-been?
My father ‭kept everything separate.
There's no single journal
that explains how the chamber works.
A-Assembly, the mechanics, the infusion process...
So then, ‭we're still missing something.
I am trying to re-create these as fast as I can,
to understand it all.
We may be running out of time.
My mother just gave Creel the Gravitonium --
a new toy for him to play with.
Creel?
What, is he ‭the -- the test subject?
That's what she says, but...
she's up to something, and I can feel it.
She wanted to join forces with S.H.I.E.L.D.,
with Daisy Johnson.
The Gravitonium is meant for you.
She can't make him into the --
The Destroyer of Worlds?
I've worked myself to the bone,
trained my whole life to become this.
And I'm so close.
I'll get you there.
I'll work harder.
I just -- I need to think.
Zephyr One, we're en route to you.
- Five minutes out. - Copy that.
You have the cargo onboard?
Yes, ma'am.
Safe and secure.
It's okay ‭if you don't want to talk.
You saw something frightening.
It's okay ‭if you're feeling scared.
I was scared of my powers, too.
I couldn't...
control it, I couldn't escape it.
But it -- it'll get better.
It will.
I promise.
I wouldn't ask you
to think about anything you don't want to.
But my friend, Phillip J. Coulson...
he's the one who helped me get better.
And right now, he's lost.
And I need...
I need to find him.
Robin, can you help me find him?
Please?
Structure looks good.
Hydraulics are okay.
I guess you didn't do any damage with all that punching.
Yeah, these things are pretty tough.
Well, if the arm fits...
So you're making arm jokes now?
I thought those were off-limits.
All right, ‭it'll be the first and last.
I'm just glad to see that these are...
...are in good shape.
Yeah, um...
I'd like to do more than...
work out and get check-ups.
Yeah?
I want you ‭to let Fitz out of his cell.
Why?
Because he knows about a weapon that General Hale wants
that uses gravity, ‭and we need to get it first.
You know what Fitz did.
Take it up with Coulson when we get him back.
And what if we can't wait for that, Mack?
Maybe it's time for others to step up.
I saw myself alive in the future.
I want to use that to help --
Damn it, Elena! That doesn't make you bulletproof.
I thought you let go of that.
There are things I can't let go of --
things I learned in the future about this team,
about Coulson, about you.
I don't want to hear about the future!
Look, all I know is,
right here, right now, you're in front of me.
Safe.
You can't protect me forever, Mack.
Did you ever stop to think maybe you're alive in the future
because I did?
Fitz stays where he is.
And so do you.
I see the future, Mr. Coulson.
You can tell the General there's nothing you can do
to make me join ‭her evil league of evil.
I'm not her messenger boy.
‭Gravitonium.
It hates you.
It wants you dead.
You don't look so great, Carl.
If you're messing ‭with that stuff, believe me,
you don't want to be the guinea pig in Hale's experiment.
S.H.I.E.L.D. is just as guilty of the same thing --
experimentation without thought of consequence.
S.H.I.E.L.D. may not be perfect,
but we'd never do ‭what Hale did to Talbot.
I thought he was your friend.
What do you mean?
You don't know.
Talbot is Hale's prisoner, too.
- She broke him. - ‭No.
She said she was getting him care no one else could.
Helping him heal.
That's a touching story.
And I should believe you instead?
You don't have to believe me because every few minutes,
a mech guard comes to check on that door,
and it's been a few minutes.
You have a choice to make, Carl.
That's a choice.
Let's see ‭if your story checks out.
If it doesn't, I'll do the same to you.
She still won't talk with me.
I thought I'd have until she was 13
before she completely tuned me out.
I'm sorry we're not able to help.
Please, do not apologize.
This -- This cannot be easy for you.
She can see the future,
and I don't even have the power to know what she's feeling.
At least when she would draw,
I'd have a window into her world.
Do you remember what her last drawing was?
I have it.
Do you know what it means?
No, Robin!
I'm not sure.
Mom?
Mommy.
I missed you.
I told you ‭Flint would get you back.
You did.
You were right.
This base is a labyrinth.
Is this the right place?
It's the only wing Hale made off-limits.
Maybe there's a reason for that.
And you can open these doors?
Yeah. Just need to know which one Talbot's in.
If what you said is true --
Straighten up and fly right, Hammond!
You look like a damn hobo!
Pretty sure that's our man.
You are in violation --
major violation of dress code 36-2903.
Noncompliance.
Get it together.
General?
Good God, man!
You sneak up on a man like that, that's not right.
That's not right.
Carl?
What the hell are you doing here?
Coulson, what the hell is Carl doing here?
He can explain it to you later.
- Are you okay to travel? - ‭Oh, no, I'm not in the best shape.
If your robot hadn't have shot him in the head.
If you still want to buy Hale's story about that, too, fine.
But can we agree this man needs to get out of here?
Listen to him, son.
He's an ally.
I'd like to get back and see my wife and child.
We good?
Yeah, let's get going.
Okay, Glenn, come on.
Perfect. Let's go.
- Come on. - Hey, you quit it! Quit being so handsy!
Glenn, I know we're under a bit of strain here,
but I'm gonna need you to use your inside voice.
- This is my inside voice! - ‭Okay.
Then your softer inside voice.
Elena, you know I don't like surprises.
Where you taking me?
If I can't convince you, someone else will.
What the hell is this?
An experiment.
The test of a hypothesis.
If that hypothesis is true,
you'll see ‭that you should let Fitz out.
I already ‭gave you my answer on that.
Yeah, but we want you to reconsider with all the facts,
so I'm going to prove that I can't be killed.
What, you, too, Simmons?
Do you know how all this sounds?
Like science.
No, sounds like ‭you're detached from reality.
Don't look at me. ‭I don't know what she's doing.
Well, what's an experiment without a little skepticism?
So, each of these beakers contain a liquid.
Three of them contain water,
the fourth holds ‭a phosphoric-acid compound
used in the hydraulics of Yo-Yo's arms --
highly toxic.
One sip will make you sick.
I mean, this much will surely kill you.
What the hell? Jemma...
- No. - Yes, Fitz.
I wouldn't be doing this if the science wasn't sound.
So, without knowing which is which,
I will drink three of them, and since I can't be killed,
I will happen to consume the three that just hold water.
This is insane.
No looking.
I'm not looking.
Are you kidding -- Simmons.
Are you serious?
Ready.
Don't do it.
- He's right. Jemma, J-- - Don't. Don't.
Simmons -- Simmons, ‭I need you to stop right now!
No-- Oh, geez.
I will now drink the last one.
And it will be water.
- No. - No.
You would shoot me ‭just to keep me from dying?
No, I-I'll wound you to stop this madness.
No.
I don't think you will.
Simmons, please.
Please, Simmons, please don't.
- Jemma - ‭Stop!
Fitz.
Jemma?
‭Jemma!
Jemma!
Simmons! Fitz! Fitz, what do I do?!
She needs some alkaloid phosphate
to counteract the toxicity!
- Where do I find that?! - I know where it is! Let me out!
Let him out!
- Please. - Let him out!
Hang on, Jemma!
Hurry up!
Elena, open the door!
Now! Open the door!
Open the door now! Ele--
A heads-up would've been nice.
You sca--
Here.
Compliments on the performance, Dame Judi Dench.
That's the longest ‭you ever kept a lie going.
It wasn't all a lie, Fitz.
I might've chosen that one.
I didn't.
Because we are invincible.
And crazy...apparently.
Let me out of here.
I'm sorry, Mack.
I know you don't understand.
But I'm doing this to keep you safe.
You're right.
I don't understand.
If, for some reason, I don't come back, it means --
We've broken the time loop.
You know my feelings on that -- it can't be broken.
Is that ‭what you'd tell our daughter,
that her world can't be changed?
Maybe, don't know. Haven't met her yet...
Oh, for goodness sake.
- ...so maybe when I clear up - ‭Guys, guys!
You argue on the way.
But if you really believe that, Fitz,
then it means we're in no danger --
Lo siento.
Lo siento, lo siento.
I'm just getting...
used to my fingers.
I'll get that.
That was close.
Let's go.
I'm glad you're here.
Me, too.
Robin...
Is this why you had stopped drawing before?
Because of what it shows?
We are going to try to make sure
that this future never happens, okay?
And to do that, we have to find --
Phillip J. Coulson.
He can put all the pieces together.
Yes.
But he's lost, and...
I'm lost without him.
Daisy, too.
That's why you need each other so much.
Yeah.
He's gonna die.
You can see that?
We can save him.
Well, once again, my life depends on
a crayon drawing ‭of a crazy person, which is...
great for me.
Is May still with her?
Yeah.
I just cannot imagine bouncing back and forth
between the past and the future like that.
It sounds terrible.
God, finally, someone gets it.
Thank you for saying that,
'cause it's been like a pretzel up here
ever since I met up with you time travelers.
Yeah, I was talking about...
Robin.
I'm sorry about your...
brain.
Coulson.
Yeah, she's seen him.
Okay, let's start searching for landmarks that might match.
It won't be easy.
But that might be where he is.
- I was brought in this way. - From where?
Any idea ‭where this bunker's located?
Well, I don't know.
I was kept in the dark, just like you, when I was brought in.
I'm right where I'm supposed to be.
Are you okay?
Can you hear them arguing?
No. What do you hear?
It's nothing. Let's keep moving.
What's wrong with him, anyway?
I'm not the only one with a cooked noodle.
Keep your hands off me.
You need to eat.
There'll be time to eat after I've reconstructed this.
What's that?
Ruby?
Creel has broken out Talbot and Coulson.
They're trying to escape. Gear up and stop them.
We need Creel alive.
You, secure Strucker.
The rest of you, go with her.
Ruby...
...alive.
I heard you.
So, where are we going?
We have coordinates to three locations,
so we'll start with the closest
and hope we don't find company when we get there.
Wait. What about our pilot?
We have an auto-pilot, which I designed.
What's the worst that could happen?
They'll be on us in seconds.
Stay behind me.
Fallen hero.
He took a shot right to the ticker.
I've got no pulse.
Oh, my God. Do something, son.
Do something!
They never agree on anything.
You're feeling it now!
They agree -- I shouldn't help him.
They? Who's "They"?
We got a man down. Come on, soldier!
Do something!
You know, you die more than anybody I've ever met.
Who do I have to thank?
Thanks, Carl.
It's time to go.
This way. This way.
If you're thinking of blond jokes, now's not the time.
- I got a bunch of 'em. - ‭Go! Go!
Fire.
I wish we had time to take you both back into hiding,
but we'll keep you safe here.
I'm just glad that Robin was able to help you.
Me, too.
We think she might've given us a location.
We'll see what we can find.
Can I ask you something?
I don't understand everything that's happened here today,
but Robin clearly has a connection with you.
I, uh...
don't know if I can explain it.
I don't fully understand it myself.
You don't have to.
I've seen the drawings.
I know that I'm not in them.
- If anything happens to me - ‭Listen...
That's not gonna happen.
Okay?
Come sit next to me, Mommy.
I don't know how to get us out.
She's blocking the only exit I know.
I guess this is how it's gonna end.
Pinned down like Butch and Sundance.
Maybe that's a cliff we can jump off.
Carl, can you open this door, too?
Yeah.
I've got something for you to absorb.
I'll hold her off.
Come on.
Kill those two.
This one's mine.
Oh, no, no!
I'm not interested in going to outer space.
I'm not a damn cosmonaut.
I think as long ‭as we avoid the altitude dial,
we should end up somewhere on Earth.
You know the Earth's 70% water, right?
I think we need to try this.
- Glenn. - ‭Yeah, okay.
Oh, boy. Here we go.
Stop!
Ruby.
Who the hell do you think you are?
I'm the Destroyer of Worlds.
Then go get them.
We're on Earth, right?
We can breathe.
I think it's good old Earth.
Well, we're in the middle of godforsaken nowhere.
We should get moving.
Hope hypothermia doesn't set in.
Maybe next time, ‭send us someplace warm, huh?
White sandy beaches and the palm trees.
That's not really my thing anymore.
We'll return in a moment.
How you got through to Garrett,
I'll never know, but thank you.
He learned to trust me, in the end.
And this is what I wanted.
Yes, but why did you care what I wanted?
I mean, to give me this.
This act cements a bond.
Yeah.
It does.
You have my undying loyalty now.
I never wanted ‭any of that Hydra nonsense.
I just wanted the Gravitonium.
Oh, no.
You misunderstand.
It wanted you.
No!