Previously on "Marvel's Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
Talbot already gave up the location of the chamber.
Yes, and we're waiting for Strucker
to show us how to put it together.
My father kept everything separate.
There's no single journal
that explains how the chamber works.
We may be running out of time.
My mother wanted to join forces with S.H.I.E.L.D.,
with Daisy Johnson.
The Gravitonium is meant for you.
- We have to find -- - Phillip J. Coulson.
Okay, let's start searching for landmarks that might match.
It won't be easy.
But that might be where he is.
Daisy's taking a long shot to find where Hale is keeping Coulson,
but we have something concrete
that can get us one step ahead of her.
Hale may be after a weapon powered by Gravitonium,
probably in a location
that Malick turned over to S.H.I.E.L.D.
We have coordinates to three locations,
so we'll start with the closest
and hope we don't find company when we get there.
Creel has broken out Talbot and Coulson.
Gear up and stop them.
Here we go.
We're on Earth, right?
Feels good to be home.
Just didn't think it'd be under these circumstances.
Did you pack the explosives?
- I did. - And the extra ammunition?
Of course.
I just want this to work.
After everything we've done to get here.
You made a choice. Don't look back.
What are the chances that we find this weapon here?
Gideon Malick hinted
that this place was a crucial R&D site for Hydra.
It's our best bet, by far.
Autopilot will land the Quinjet somewhere nearby,
keep it cloaked until we get back.
Ready if you are.
So ready.
I was thinking we could come back to England
for our honeymoon -- if we ever got one.
Sounds perfect!
Don't make me the third wheel, guys.
No trouble with the straps this time.
We've come a long way!
I got to take five.
No, no, no. No, no, no. We could've been followed.
We can't stop now. Come on.
Come on. What do you care?
You left me alone for months, Phil.
I'm sure you can manage another couple of minutes, can't you?
Don't jump down his throat. He's all you got.
For what it's worth,
I'm sorry ‭we didn't find you sooner.
Now come on.
Just trying to hold out, Phil.
Where were you?
We were in the future.
You were in the future.
What, do you guys live in some fifth-dimension freak show?
I'd say that's a ‭relatively accurate description
- of our day-to-day life. - Yeah, well, not mine.
If we get out of here, I'm -- I'm done!
I'm too jumbled as it is.
You gonna let someone like Hale get the best of you?
She broke me, Phil.
I let down the Air Force, my country...
...and I let down my family.
I'm not gonna be able to look Carla in the eye again.
I promise you, no one's gonna see it that way.
Yeah? Well, I do.
It's kind of a moot point
if we freeze to death out here, isn't it?
That's why we got to keep moving.
We're never gonna find them.
We've been circling the Trident Range for hours,
and there's still no sign of Coulson and whoever he's with.
Well, that's a surprise,
considering we're following such a detailed map.
Robin's been right about everything else.
Yeah, well, ‭what if this doesn't happen
for another month or -- or a year?
Would it kill her to draw a calendar?
Why don't you go ask her?
Well, I thought that I left all this prophecy crap back in the future.
Deke, you're not helping.
Maybe we should change tactics.
What are you thinking?
The cloud cover's too thick to see through anyway.
We should land, canvass the area on foot,
let Coulson find us.
Hale's hideout could be nearby. We'd be exposed.
Give him a shot.
If you think it's the right call.
Davis, find a place to set her down.
Okay. Where'd you have in mind?
Anywhere.
We should start looking for shelter.
Maybe get a fire going.
Were you ever a Boy Scout?
Brigadier General ‭outranks a Boy Scout, Coul--
Run.
No, come on. We got to keep moving. Come on.
You got your powers back.
It's a long story. May, get them back to the Zephyr.
- I'll take care of her. - Not a chance.
It's a rescue mission. Look at them.
So, how'd you find us?
Robin.
A little bit like cheating, don't you think?
Keep moving.
And, Deke, watch their back. That's an order.
The legendary Quake.
You know, you're much prettier in person.
And meaner, so I'd stay where you are.
It's funny.
I have your poster up on my wall.
You're like that, uh...hero...
that every little girl wants to be when they grow up.
Looks like you made a wrong turn along the way.
No.
I'm just engineered differently.
I don't want to be you.
I want to beat you.
You can certainly try.
I don't think ‭she's getting up from that.
What are you still doing here?
I thought she had you for a sec, but --
Deke!
We got to get out of here. Let's go.
I need an extraction team at this location.
Get this plane in the air.
We got you.
I can't stop the bleeding.
Grab the hemostatic granules.
It's okay.
Come on.
Scissors.
Hope this thing has instructions.
- Okay, hold him still. - That's not a good sign.
- It's working. - This is only a temporary fix.
He's gonna need ‭actual medical attention.
Call ahead to Simmons. Give her a heads-up.
No one's answering.
Can you hold on until we make it to the Lighthouse?
Just get us there as fast as you can.
It's about damn time.
The code is 6-2-8-8-2.
What the hell? Is Fitz evil again?
Yo-Yo and Simmons broke him out.
W-why? Where did they go?
Looks like there may be a way in up here.
Radiation poisoning would be a whole new way
to find out we can still die.
- Should we turn back? - No need.
Primula vulgaris -- primrose.
I used to pick these as a girl.
I mean, it's a hardy species,
but even it couldn't survive in irradiated soil.
You'll find more radiation in a dentist's office.
Talbot probably just posted these signs to keep out interlopers.
They won't scare off Hydra.
Let me.
Well, looks like getting your arms chopped off isn't all bad.
The -- Well -- Yeah -- It is -- Obviously, it's bad.
It's really bad getting your arms chopped off,
but maybe there is a silver lining --
Well, as much as I'm enjoying this day in the country,
we have a job to do.
After you, better half.
Here, take these.
We're landing soon.
That was reckless back there, Deke.
You this kind to everybody who takes a bullet for you?
- You were the reason we had to retreat. - Well, I'm sorry.
Next time, I'll try to keep all my blood inside of my body.
I had Hale's daughter down for the count.
We could've captured her.
Yeah, she was down, and I was trying to secure her weapon,
like any other agent would have.
- You're not an agent. - Oh, really?
Well, then maybe you should stop ordering me around like one, then.
Because this top-dog thing doesn't suit you.
What does it matter if you don't listen?
I can't fight and protect your dumb ass at the same time.
You are the worst.
I -- I was trying to give you backup...
I didn't need your backup!
Even though you threatened to kill me
a couple of dozen times --
Here. Have some water.
Deke.
We need help over here!
Now!
Mack, where have you been?
Get Simmons. We need her.
She's not here. She and Yo-Yo locked me in Fitz's cell
and ran off to who knows where.
Fitz's cell?
Must be the long story you mentioned.
Yeah. I left you in charge. What the hell happened?
They think they can't be killed.
You try arguing with someone who's totally irrational.
We'll decide who's rational later.
- What are we gonna do for Deke? - He's coughing up blood.
If Simmons is AWOL, we have to get him to a hospital.
We don't have time for that.
Piper, you were in training
to be a field medic for the strike team.
- What are we looking at? - Uh, he's in shock.
If he doesn't get a blood transfusion soon --
No choice. Treat him here.
I have zero field experience. There's no way.
- I'm not a surgeon. - Just talk me through it.
I'm not afraid of blood, and I got a steady hand.
You should put some ice on that.
That's not necessary.
- I need you at your best. - When am I not?
You know, I could've beaten Daisy Johnson today
if you hadn't forced her to run.
Too much of a risk. She's got an unfair advantage.
Once we complete our objective,
you'll be able to beat her without breaking a sweat.
So move up the timetable, then.
No, not until Creel tells us more about the Gravitonium.
Now get in.
Are you serious?
You went against my orders, nearly murdered Creel.
- We need him for this. - For what?
He's dangerous.
He's completely out of your control.
Yes, as are you.
That's why I'm putting you both back in your cage.
Do I need to force you?
Power's being diverted to a space on the second floor,
but according to this plan, there's nothing there.
Bad guys rarely mark their evil lairs on blueprints.
We'll find a way to locate it once we get inside.
We may have to improvise that bit.
We're improving all the bits.
Any idea what the weapon in there is?
We'll blow it up regardless.
Hold on.
I'm reading ‭an encrypted radio signal.
Coming from where?
Coming here. Move.
Inside.
Anton Ivanov is providing security.
Means we're in the right place.
And that we've lost our advantage.
A man who can't die, huh?
Maravilloso.
Almost cleaned out.
Okay. Where do we go from here?
I think he has a hemothorax -- blood in his chest cavity.
We need to stop the bleeding and drain it.
You're gonna need to cut into the wound
so we can see what we're doing.
- What about anesthesia? - Well, he's already unconscious,
and I haven't read that chapter yet,
so we'll just figure it out as we go.
So, this kid's from the future?
Yeah. And in that future, Earth is gone,
and the last of humanity is enslaved by alien overlords.
Alien...over...
I should've stayed in my cell.
You're telling me that we got our asses handed to us
by little green men.
They were big and blue.
But they didn't crack the world apart.
They said it was Daisy.
And you're still sending her on missions?
I need her leading missions.
I got an old injury acting up.
Not sure what my timetable is, exactly.
Oh, for the love of flapjacks.
Do you ever have any good news?
There's a young Inhuman who's seen a better future.
We're working toward that.
Anything else we can do for him?
We're here if they need a hand.
Can I talk to you for a second?
We need to talk about Fitz-Simmons and Yo-Yo.
If they really believe they can't be killed --
That's not the conversation we're having right now.
Then, what conversation are we having right now?
Well, the one where you explain
all the stupid decisions you've been making recently.
That's rather specific.
Giving yourself up to Hale was a mistake.
She was about to blow up the Zephyr.
- What did you want me to do? - I don't know.
Stall her long enough for me to get to the cockpit.
You hold on while I throw the plane
into a vertical dive, maybe.
- Knock out Creel -- -You gonna get to a point?
My point is, you didn't even try.
You just rolled over without a fight.
I did what I thought was best, and it got results.
We rescued Talbot ‭and learned about Hale's agenda.
Yeah, and nearly lost Deke in the process.
He should've listened to Daisy.
Well, maybe Daisy shouldn't have been put in that position
in the first place.
You don't think she should lead?
I didn't say that.
But she does need time. She's questioning herself.
- I question myself every day -- - Let me speak.
All Daisy could think about was getting you back.
She's not ready for your job, Phil.
She has to be. My time is running out.
Because you're being irresponsible.
You said you weren't in a hurry to die,
but you're not acting like it.
So this isn't so much about my stupidity
as it is about me dying.
Seems like one thing led to the other.
You realize this isn't easy for me, but I've accepted it.
Which is the problem.
Maybe I'm reckless.
But if this is the end,
better to go out ‭doing something that matters.
No.
You don't get to make that decision alone.
That decision is made with the people who love you.
- May - and that's me.
I love you.
I thought that would shut you up.
You're not supposed to be here.
I wanted you to know before her.
It's all here.
Are you ready?
She won't let me.
Why?
More tests.
Creel betrayed us,
but she'll still listen to every word that he says.
You said this was ours.
You don't have to follow her orders anymore.
She locked me in here. I don't have a choice.
Of course you do.
You could tear her apart if you wanted to.
So why don't you?
I don't know.
The mechs are still sending signals back and forth.
- We should keep following it. - And then sneak past them?
Yeah, call that plan A.
Plan A seems ambitious.
Well
that's why we have a plan B.
Yes, General, we have found the chamber.
We are looking it over as we speak.
We'll join you as soon as Strucker finishes the plans.
Keep it secure until then.
That will not be a problem so long as you keep your word.
You'll have your chance with the chamber.
Another step toward becoming the superior man.
I hope it is as powerful as you promised.
As do I.
What was that?
Nothing I can't handle.
What were those mechs guarding?
This isn't connected to a water main.
Just destroy all of it.
Should've brought more explosives.
Won't be long until they realize
we've slipped through their defenses...
We can cut out its heart once we work out what this thing does,
and to whom.
Mr. Ivanov -- ‭you think he could be trusted?
For the moment, ‭his interests align with mine.
He wants to be first into the chamber.
I want to see what it does to human flesh.
Would you like me to accompany you?
No, I want you to stay focused on our contingency plan.
You know the message that needs to be sent.
Of course, General.
Ruby.
You didn't think I'd still be here.
I assumed Strucker opened the door.
I'm surprised you're not with him right now.
Where would we go?
It doesn't matter if there's a lock on that door or not.
I'd never run from you.
I've kept you safe.
You've kept me obedient.
And I've let you control me.
And I have no idea why.
Ruby, I have great plans for you.
Like Whitehall had great plans for you?
You have always said that you wanted a choice,
but you've never given me one.
I-I know that I've demanded a lot from you recently,
- but I - No, Mom, you've demanded the impossible,
and I have tried to be
everything that you wanted me to be.
- I tried to eliminate weakness. - I know, I know.
I tried to be you! I've passed every test,
and I've learned every lesson and I'm not enough!
I never said that.
I'm a disappointment.
You said that, Mom.
And after everything that you've done to me,
I've kept trying,
because all I've ever wanted to do is please you.
Ruby...
You're my one weakness, Mom.
And I'm yours.
Ruby, stop.
I'll make you proud.
Get that ready for transport -- now.
How'd it go?
We're free and clear.
Daisy.
General. It's okay. It's okay.
Sorry. You startled me.
It's bad enough I look like a bottle brush.
Yeah, well, you probably can't look at me
without remembering... what happened.
Not always in the driver seat.
I know you didn't try and kill me.
I know that was a skin-job.
Still, I'm -- I'm really sorry.
I should apologize to you.
You came on a rescue mission to try and save me.
It went south. No, it's too high of a risk.
You should never have brought me here.
It's -- it's okay, General.
Um I brought you a change of clothes.
Is there anything else you need?
Thank you.
I'd like to talk to my wife.
You know, just to tell her I'm safe.
I'm sorry.
Hale is still looking for us.
We -- We can't have any contact with the outside world.
We have to stay dark.
I said cat -- cat!
I scared George, and...
I need to talk to my son.
I need him to know I haven't forgotten him.
I'm sure he knows how much you love him.
I abandoned him, Agent Johnson!
You don't get a second chance to fix a screw-up like that.
Maybe I can get word to them through a secure channel.
That's all I'm asking for.
But that's not why you're here, is it.
We're trying to figure out our next move.
I need you to tell me what you can
about the site Hale kept you in and...
...I need you to tell me
everything you told her about us.
This could take a while.
Well, that didn't take long.
She won't work without this component.
And the machine does what, exactly?
An Adaptive Particle Processor.
Scans an element at the atomic level,
and then this component converts it
to be merged with the recipient's DNA.
We think it's the same technology
that gave Carl Creel his powers,
only his abilities are temporary and require physical touch.
Yeah, but the machine's been upgraded,
so if Hale were to use Gravitonium --
Yeah, yeah, I get it. No gizmo, no apocalypse.
But there's always a chance that we've tried this before.
More than a chance.
Previous selves probably came here,
made all the same decisions,
still failed to change the timeline.
You spoke to your older self in the future.
Did she give you any clues,
any specific ways to stop this all from happening again?
We didn't have much time.
I haven't told anyone this, not even Mack.
I didn't want to put this on the team.
What is it?
We have to let Coulson die.
What? That -- That doesn't make sense.
The other me, she said...
trying to save him is what led to the end.
But...how --
Time to improvise an exit strategy.
You guys open one of the doors, whoosh, whoosh,
I take their guns, ‭
we shoot the robots, we go home.
Sounds brilliant to me.
Mack is going to be sad to miss this.
Yo-Yo. Yo-Yo, what's going on?
Is that furrowed brow about our patient or about Yo-Yo?
One minute, I'm... terrified for her,
and the next minute, I'm furious with her.
Elena's always been stubborn, but ever since her arms...
Yeah, well, if I hadn't let Hale --
No, don't do that.
- You made a mistake. -Yeah, a big mistake.
Like, how do you even begin to make up for something like that?
...you fix something else.
That's why I like engines, putting the pieces together --
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Piper, what do we do?
Uh, we have to find the source of the bleeding.
All right, the bullet's in there.
Must've nicked an artery.
All right, step two.
You have to clamp the artery
before his blood pressure drops any more.
Did not think ‭I'd be doing this today.
Damn it, stay still.
We're trying to help you.
He's stablised.
That's step two.
Yeah. Well, we're gonna have to wait to high-five.
Step three is, you sew his artery shut
so he doesn't bleed out and die.
- We need a new plan. - What happened out there?
I don't know. I was using my speed,
and it felt like my arms were being ripped off.
The mech arms aren't built to go that fast.
The interface is transmitting
every electrical signal simultaneously.
It's overloading your nervous system.
I don't need an explanation! I need a solution!
I can't recalibrate them,
not here, not before that door gives out.
Take cover there.
Fitz and I will draw them away from the exits,
keep them occupied.
You find a way out,
make it to the Quinjet, call for backup.
I can fight. ‭I think one of you should --
No. We have a rule.
We never leave ‭each other's side anymore.
Duck.
I'm sorry you never got the honeymoon you dreamed of.
Nonsense.
I'm protecting England from evil robots with the man I love.
Oh, it's jammed!
Go back, go back!
Running low.
I don't know what we were thinking.
There you are.
Please tell me you still believe time can't be changed.
You want to debate that now? Isn't --
Isn't that why we're here?
No, Fitz, just tell me it's against the law of physics.
I need that right now.
- The perception of time is an illusion. - Last mag.
According to Hermann Minkowski, space-time --
No, you know, I was wrong. It's not helping.
I heard what happened to you.
Now you are also part machine.
Not the part that matters.
I no longer feel pain.
Unlike you.
I have died dozens of times.
But you, no second chances.
Part machine.
Who's superior now?
He was controlling them.
- Welcome back. - You are on a lot of drugs.
But, hey, good news -- you didn't die.
Thank you.
You guys saved me.
Well, we're just glad you pulled through.
Is Daisy here?
She's so pretty.
What now?
I want to put my mouth on her mouth and move it around a lot.
But I don't want to do that unless she wants to, too,
'cause that's what makes it nice.
But I don't think she wants that,
'cause she does not like me one bit.
I mean, she's -- she's not my type,
but I -- I get it.
Okay, Spaceman, maybe we should --
Ma-a-a-a-a-ck!
Dude!
You are so cool.
Do we know any handshakes?
Uh, I appreciate that, but --
Should I shave my head?
Yeah, no, I see no flaws in that plan.
Maybe then Daisy would like me, because she -- she protected me.
She's very smart.
Would it hurt him if I turn this up?
- Yeah, I don't think so. - Good.
I also -- Ooh. My brain is falling --
Hey, something weird just happened.
I-I wouldn't.
Uh, remember the signal transceivers from the mechs?
Yeah.
We got a ping.
We're tracing it.
They're not damaged. They just went offline.
Perhaps something Yo-Yo did?
Yeah.
Whatever it is, we're safe...for now.
Still can't believe we survived.
Me neither.
But you were so certain we'd be fine.
"Time is fixed" And all that.
I started having my doubts.
Maybe your hopeful nature's rubbing off on me.
Aww, how cute.
Well, looks like you two have made quite the mess.
It's not the first time.
They were there when S.H.I.E.L.D. tortured me.
No.
They destroyed a component for the infuser.
It's useless.
We can't transfer the Gravitonium until it's repaired.
Fix it.
Or bleed out.
Fitz, we can't let it happen again.
We don't have a choice.
We never did.
We'll return in a moment.
I thought you'd like to know that we got a lead on Hale.
You really helped.
I wouldn't go that far.
I also thought about what you said about your son.
And, um...if -- if I would've known
that my dad cared growing up,
it would've made a big difference.
Um, so, it took some doing,
uh, but this phone was set to bounce
through a dozen foreign relays.
We only have one shot, and even then, just a few minutes.
But you can call them, without Hale tracing us.
Thank you.
Hello?
Hi, honey. It's Glenn.
Oh, Glenn.
I was so worried.
I know. I'm -- I'm so sorry.
Once the Air Force took you, I-I got a few progress reports,
but then you never called.
I thought I'd never see you again.
Honey, I'm sorry. I only have a few minutes.
I-I just want you to tell George that his dad's okay
and his father loves him very much.
And I'm getting better.
I'm getting stronger, and I'm...
I'm not yelling...as much.
- Glenn... - Yeah?
The doctors said you should take a deep breath.
Calm your mind.
You know what is best.
What is best is you comply.
Remember, your compliance will be rewarded.
Glenn, are you ready to comply?
I'm happy to.