If there's a chance to save
your life, why not try?
What if Cybertek
has the key to saving you?
Cybertek is the same company
that built Deathlok's leg.
- The answer's no.
- About that Deathlok program...
I'm gonna do some digging,
see what else I can find.
Glenn, are you ready to comply?
I'm happy to.
Talbot, stop. Why are you trying
to get into the hangar?
♪♪
[Air hissing]
She's the Destroyer.
[Screams]
♪♪
Ruby! No!
Yo-Yo, what did you do?!
- I found what you're looking for.
- QOVAS: My Gravitonium.
S.H.I.E.L.D. has it.
But they won't give it willingly.
You'd have me kill them?
I have no reason to stop you.
05x19 - Option Two
TALBOT: 4-3 point 9-4-6-2
dash 7-6 point 1-1-9-1.
4-3 point 9-4-6-2
4-3 point 9-4-6-2...
COULSON: Once Zephyr One breaks
through the upper atmosphere,
we can slingshot the Gravitonium
at high velocity into the Sun,
destroying it for good.
As anxious as we are
to contain an element
that may cause the future
destruction of the planet,
we have to get Zephyr ready
for space travel first.
"Future destruction"?
It's complicated. Just go with it.
- So, how close are we?
- On the Zephyr,
RCS thrusters are operational.
On the Gravitonium...
SIMMONS: We're nearly finished
extracting residual traces
from the machine,
which seems to have refined
the element in some way.
DEKE: Should be enough to power
the pseudo-gravity engine.
So, in other words, we're close.
I've kind of been consulting, so...
MAY: Meanwhile, Carl Creel
still needs medical help.
And I think we should
get Robin and Polly
somewhere safe, too.
After General Talbot...
- He's not going anywhere.
- I know.
But I've been talking to Tony Caine.
What, my Tony? The Candyman?
He's arranged for Creel's treatment,
and he says
he could take care
of Robin and Polly... for now.
- Great. Do it. Maybe Davis can...
- I'll take them.
It's the least I can do after
dragging them out of hiding.
Unless there's some objection.
♪♪
No. They'll be safer than here.
Well, make it quick.
General Hale's MIA,
and I doubt she took
an early retirement.
Wait, explain to me how she got away.
Didn't you have them contained?
Yeah, we did.
That girl was a ticking bomb.
And she went off
when you cut her throat.
A gravity surge knocked everyone back
and disrupted our equipment.
She slipped away.
I was afraid you'd have to quake Ruby
and crack the Earth.
That shouldn't even be an issue,
speaking of cutthroat.
- All right, let's keep it productive.
- There'd already be a crack
in the universe if you hadn't.
Look, I did what I did.
I'm not proud,
but it was the right choice.
It was revenge.
You let your emotions
get the best of you.
Ruby should be locked up,
and she's not the only one.
All I did was kill the person
called the Destroyer of Worlds.
That's what Daisy was called. We're
lucky you didn't cut her throat.
Just stop, Deke. The point is,
you don't make that decision.
Then who does? You?
We all have blood on our hands.
Why am I being singled out?
That's not what we do here.
This is S.H.I.E.L.D. We protect.
She was a psychopath.
- Ask Fitz.
- Yeah, just look at his cracked rib.
If you'd have seen what she was like,
- this never would've...
- I didn't get a chance.
I was too busy screaming
to be let out of a cell.
Fitz shouldn't have even been there.
- We delayed their plan!
- If we hadn't gone, Ruby would be free.
YO-YO: But this isn't about
the decision, is it?
This is about not following your orders.
It's about both.
Well, we didn't pick you.
♪♪
Coulson made that decision
and brought you back
when he could have broken
that loop right there!
All right, stop it.
♪♪
Yes, I made that decision,
and I'll be making the rest today.
It's over.
Go do your jobs.
♪♪
So, is this normal?
A weird mission? Yeah.
The fighting? That's new.
♪♪
Here to ask me if I'm okay?
Not if I don't have to.
Good.
Then tell me what the Candyman's got.
Thinks he found something
connected to
the Deathlok program, Garrett.
Could be a stretch, but...
It could keep Coulson alive.
Whether he likes it or not.
So Creel's been put on board?
And he's on an I.V. drip,
so he's not a danger to anyone.
Once you have him, Robin, and
her mom set up, go dark.
I'll cover for you here.
Okay.
Thank you for being sane.
Robin said someday Coulson will
put all the pieces together.
That has to mean something.
♪♪
DEKE: But not according
to the multiverse theory.
Mm.
I'm not sure you actually know
what "multiverse" means.
That every choice we make
spins out a different timeline
into the cosmos,
and right now, there are
infinite parallel universes.
[Machinery whirring, beeping]
But I am proof
that you can move between them.
Or...
you're proof that we are
in one timeline, in a loop...
an infinite, intractable,
unchangeable loop.
But if we succeed in ridding
the planet of Gravitonium,
then we break that loop and
prevent the Earth's destruction.
Which is great,
because that definitely
won't affect me at all.
[Air hisses]
♪♪
Look, it's not like I'm just
gonna blink out of existence.
I lived in one timeline,
but now I live in this new one,
and I think I'm gonna stay
in the one with the sun
and tacos and all that,
because that's the multiverse.
That's science.
Or you're a canary in a coal mine.
I don't know
what either of those things are.
♪♪
We won't know if we're successful
at changing the future unless
you blink out of existence.
Fitz...
FITZ: Jemma agrees.
She actually wrote a paper
on the theory of...
Nobody knows how it works.
Now, be careful.
This substance
is extremely unpredictable.
Just make sure that
that gets to the Zephyr in o...
No, okay. You know what? I think
I might take that myself.
Oh, quit it!
I carried this stuff around
on my belt for years, okay?
Y... And didn't you guys make a pledge
never to leave each other's side?
You have to do that.
You have to keep that pledge for the...
you know, the... good of humanity.
Your humanity, you mean.
I appreciate how invested
you are in our future,
but for now, let's worry about
the future of the planet.
♪♪
4-3 point...
9-4-6-2 dash 7-6 point 1-1-9-1.
♪♪
Coulson.
Coulson!
♪♪
4-3 point 9-4-6-2
dash 7-6 point 1-1-9-1.
THOMAS: He's been yelling for you.
I can fix this.
Wait by the door.
4-3... 4-3 point 9-4-6-2...
♪♪
Phil.
It's like a record that just
keeps skipping in my head, the numbers.
♪♪
I was... I was with Robin.
Okay. Calm down.
But I was at the control box.
Why? W-What was I doing there?
Trying to get the doors open?
I'm Air Force, Phil.
I know enough about navigational aids
to know that every hangar
has a landing...
assist.
♪♪
I had to comply.
The landing-assist beacon.
♪♪
The only way to get a signal out.
4-3 point 9-4-6-2
dash 7-6 point 1-1-9-1.
Phil, tell me
that's not what I think it is.
♪♪
Our location.
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
[Alarm blaring]
It came out of nowhere.
Any word from outside?
They jammed our communications
and exterior cameras.
As far as we can tell, both the
Lighthouse and River's End
have been cut off
from the rest of the world.
That's not reassuring.
STONER: Greetings, elite
citizens of the Lighthouse.
Project Reclamation has been triggered.
It appears you're experiencing
an apocalypse-level event.
Aw, this guy again?
Please remain calm.
This moment in human history
is what this bunker was designed for.
That actually is kind of reassuring.
Please go to the main computer terminal
and choose from the following options.
If the Lighthouse is experiencing
an extreme-weather event, press 1.
Agent Coulson,
I can't silence the alarms.
If you're experiencing
a nuclear attack, press 2.
Screw it.
- For an alien invasion, press 3.
- Aw...
You have selected nuclear attack.
For your own health, safety,
and radiation protection,
all outer doors will remain
sealed for 15 years.
Did he just say 15 years?
How was I supposed to know there
would be an "alien invasion" option?
You always listen to the whole menu.
Always! [groans]
[Computer beeping]
[Alarm blaring]
[P.A. feedback]
You may be noticing
that the Lighthouse
is going into lockdown mode.
This is not a drill.
The Lighthouse is keeping us safe.
All exits, including the hangar,
have been sealed to protect us
from any outside intrusion.
Which is good, 'cause there is currently
a sizeable alien spaceship overhead.
Oh, and due to a technical malfunction,
the Lighthouse thinks
we're under nuclear attack,
so we may be trapped inside
for 15 years... ish.
No, no, no. No, no, no, no, no!
I am... I am so stupid.
Why am I still in here?
I'm sure there's a way around that.
So in the meantime,
there's no reason to panic.
The Lighthouse survives
the Earth cracking apart,
so one flying saucer,
probably no big deal.
STONER: All Lighthouse survival
systems are operational.
Good luck. You're humanity's last hope.
Your survival is essential...
[Electricity crackles]
♪♪
Ugh. Now what?
Oh. Hey.
I know this guy.
QOVAS: Phil Coulson.
Humanity's shield.
Yeah, I remember you, too.
The lighting wasn't great,
but the whole vision thing
was hard to forget.
Did General Hale send you?
You will be dealing with me now.
I'm here for what was promised...
the Gravitonium.
Yeah, that's gonna be a hard pass.
Maybe you haven't realized it yet,
but this bunker...
it's apocalypse-proof.
It can withstand a nuclear blast.
We have years of food, water, and air.
- Is that true?
- Not good food.
And pretty soon,
the world's gonna realize
there's this giant ship
in its atmosphere,
and I'm thinking, in the current
political climate,
won't be long before
you're blown out of the sky.
♪♪
Too much?
If you're here for the update,
tell Coulson the communication
relay doesn't work, either.
We don't have time for this.
We might be stuck in here for 15 years.
You think you can avoid me
for that long?
- I want to explain.
- Which part?
- I was trying to save you.
- Yeah...
Not this again.
You need to listen.
You saw her... me in the future.
I spoke to her.
She warned me of all of this.
I don't want to hear it,
and I don't want to know.
She was trying to help us, Mack,
to prevent this,
to keep me from losing you.
She said things that...
And it's making you crazy.
This whole future thing
has got you all acting crazy.
I don't want to know.
I'm just trying to fix the
problems right in front of me,
not get my mind twisted trying
to figure out what comes next.
We already saw what comes next!
So you're willing to do anything,
no matter who it hurts!
We've been through too much.
It messed you up.
♪♪
Thanks for the reminder, Mack.
You don't even look at me the same.
♪♪
You know that's not what I meant.
No wonder you're pulling away.
You're pushing me away.
Y-You think I don't care about
what happened to your arms?
You don't care enough.
How can you not want that girl
to suffer for what she did?!
I wanted to beat her senseless,
but that's not what we do!
That's not us! We turn the other cheek.
Would you say that to May?
Huh?
That she could've saved
that little girl in Bahrain?
No.
Because she made
the tough choice to save lives.
In the Framework,
you saw the alternative.
In the future...
we swore...
♪♪
We swore we wouldn't lose ourselves.
I know.
Or lose each other.
I love you.
I'm doing this for you,
but you need to believe me.
You need to trust
that I know what I'm doing.
Please, Mack.
You know me.
You know I may run away,
but I always come back
to where I started.
♪♪
I know.
I just don't know
if I'll be here when you do.
♪♪
[Sighs]
Mack?
Um, says the relay's done.
That's all he said?
[Chuckles] No.
♪♪
Look, I can't tell you
if what you did was right or wrong.
That's up to you to decide.
But it doesn't just change you.
It changes how people see you.
And the only thing you can do
is make peace with it.
♪♪
I'm trying.
Daisy should be back by now.
I can't get a line out.
But you should be able
to get a signal in, right?
What if she never made it
out of our airspace at all?
YO-YO: Who would know? Can't we try...
- What if that ship fired on them?
- Daisy's fine.
♪♪
She's gone dark.
Daisy's mission wasn't just about
Robin, Polly, and Creel.
She's following a lead.
A lead on what?
- A way to keep you alive.
- What?
I don't want that.
My orders are very clear about that.
If there's a chance we can save you,
- don't you think I'd take it?
- Right now, we all need saving
from our new overlords out there,
and our most powerful
team member's gone.
YO-YO: No, no, no, no, no.
I killed Ruby for nothing.
It didn't matter.
It's all happening right now.
- Everything she told me.
- "She" who?
This right here...
this is how we lose.
♪♪
I could've warned myself
about a lot of things...
Ruby, Hale, these aliens...
but instead, she told me...
♪♪
Instead, she told me,
"Coulson is dying,
and we need to let him."
♪♪
I'm sorry, sir.
I hated keeping this. I owe you so much.
♪♪
You're my family.
No, you're wrong.
Robin said Coulson
puts the pieces back together.
And you're saying
that we should've just left him
to freeze to death
in the middle of nowhere.
I have to listen, May.
- The middle of nowhere...
- She was me.
She's lived through this,
through the loop,
- who knows how many times.
- Exactly... you don't know.
We haven't lost yet,
and as far as we know,
they can't get in here,
- and until they do...
- They can go wherever they want.
...you better believe we're
gonna do everything possible
to keep him alive.
They can go wherever they want.
♪♪
[Electricity crackling]
- [Electricity crackles]
- [Groans]
♪♪
[Electricity crackling]
[Gunshots]
[Grunts]
[Chokes, gasping]
♪♪
Sensors, the cameras...
everything's glitchy.
You getting the same thing I am?
Energy fluctuations all
over the Lighthouse? Yeah.
Which could mean they're already inside.
♪♪
They're already inside!
- We don't even know who "they" are.
- [Panting]
I do.
The Remorath are marauders.
They're intergalactic scavengers
with no planet of their own,
so they just take from others,
and... and wherever they go,
- darkness follows.
- MAY: Darkness?
- That's a little vague.
- Well, it's not the concept of darkness,
it's literal darkness.
It follows them because they're magic,
and they can see in the dark,
and we can't,
so it makes them kill us better
with... with their claws.
Did you say "claws"?
Yeah. Did I not mention
the footlong razor claws?
Because, yeah.
Well, people in the future survive.
There must be a way to stop them.
No, we didn't stop them.
We just... We just gave them
whatever they wanted,
and then... said thank you and...
cleaned up the bodies after they left.
♪♪
All right, this is no longer a siege,
this is an evacuation.
Fitz-Simmons, see if you can find a way
to override the whole
nuclear-contamination protocol.
We need to get the Zephyr
airborne and out of here,
preferably with the Gravitonium
and our people on board.
How are your arms feeling?
Fitz recalibrated them, so I'm like new.
Good, because we also need
to get Talbot out of lockup,
and we have no idea what
kind of influence he's under.
Well, if he makes a move,
I'll make a faster one.
Great. Thank you.
Coulson, I think
we might have something.
There's a... There's an analogue
override on floor 17.
It's the system I check
after the beacon explodes,
so I can rig up a bypass.
All right, if we can get
the hangar doors open
and Deke and I can get the engines
going, we're in business.
SIMMONS: I'll ready
the Gravitonium for travel.
We've got Piper and Davis here to help,
and, uh, Fitz can
take Agent Wahl for backup.
No, Simmons, you... you are the backup.
You guys made a pledge not
to leave each other's side,
so I feel like...
Well, we don't really have much choice.
You... You can get Daisy
to give you backup.
She's strong,
and she's protective, and she...
Wait. Can't...
Wait. Can't Daisy just
quake us out of here?
Why isn't she back yet?
Ask May.
♪♪
All settled?
Weird kid.
Drew me a picture of a blue lady
juggling someone's balls.
♪♪
Pretty sure they were her balls.
Aliens, you know?
[Sighs]
Have you seen all this weird stuff
happening in New York?
I can't watch the news.
It makes me crazy.
Look, I got to get back, so...
Agent Johnson, you know why
they call me the Candyman?
Because the Candyman can?
Project Deathlok had a lot of branches.
There's a very complex web to untangle.
A lot of promises were made,
- promises were broken and...
- Tony.
All right. Short story long,
it all goes back to this one Hydra dude
named John Garrett.
Yeah, I'm familiar.
He was being kept alive
by this secret sauce...
all kinds of ingredients.
He called it Centipede serum.
I think from the shape of it.
That's... That's the last one, so...
Don't waste it.
I'm familiar.
This is, uh, a start. Thank you.
Yeah, well,
the thing about it is, though,
Garrett's cocktail
had an extra healing component
that was designed
and developed by the Nazis,
so that's impossible to get.
Nothing's impossible.
It's one element. What is it?
I have no idea.
All I got was the name of
some place where they found it.
And I can't find it on any map.
♪♪
[Sighs]
That's 'cause it's not a place.
Come on, Glenn.
Just think.
You can fix this, you can fix this.
- [Inhales deeply] Just think.
- [Tapping on glass]
♪♪
- Speedy!
- Don't.
Back up.
♪♪
[Panel beeping, lock clicks]
Bad aliens are coming,
and we're getting out.
Coulson's orders. Come on.
Oh, sorry. I can't do that.
♪♪
I caused this problem.
You give me a gun,
I'll help take out
as many of them as I can.
Better yet, you know what you do?
You get me a phone,
and I'll call in an air strike.
There's no way to call out.
Then I'll send up a smoke signal.
You're not Air Force anymore.
♪♪
Okay, look, there's no need for that.
We're fine.
That's not necessary,
because I-I'll comply.
I'll... That's a bad choice of words.
I'll... cooperate.
♪♪
[Handcuffs click]
Sorry.
Has to be done.
I'll make up for what I did.
Make it right for that little girl.
Robin and her... mother.
I believe you,
but we don't know
if you're the one in control.
- Okay.
- So you follow my lead.
[Speaking Spanish]
♪♪
SIMMONS: Do you think Deke's right?
Let me be clear... Deke is never right.
We're in radio contact.
We're not split up. We're just...
[Electricity crackles]
♪♪
Jemma?
Jemma, do you copy?
[Electricity crackles]
We should go.
♪♪
[Electricity crackling]
[Breathing heavily]
[Grunts]
No, no, no, no.
Let's move.
♪♪
Oh, come on, come on, come on.
[Tapping]
[Breathing heavily]
♪♪
[Groans]
Get back!
[Shrieking]
♪♪
Shh, shh! Shh, shh, shh!
[Breathing heavily]
What are you doing here?
Without you, there is no me.
Never been, uh, so happy to meet
someone so self-serving.
If anyone asks,
we scared that thing off, okay?
Or he knew he could just kill us later.
[Electricity crackles]
Don't tell me that's the override.
How the hell did he find that thing?
The Lighthouse is enormous.
Doesn't matter.
This was our only way out.
♪♪
All of you see where you're going,
where to find it.
Then lay waste to anyone
who stands in our way.
♪♪
Evac is a no-go.
Fitz says the override's been destroyed.
They have the layout of this place?
Who knows? They have teleportation tech,
and they did show me
visions of far-off places.
They'd be great to have on our
team if they were interested.
- They may have a layout of this place.
- So, new plan?
Yeah, we rally together, make a stand.
Well, those doors
aren't gonna hold for long.
I don't like our chances
without more ammo.
We'll make it to the armory
and bring back what we can find.
Thanks, Agent Kim.
A team of us is gonna take up
a defensive position
here in Control.
Secure whatever firepower
you can, then head our way.
- You copy?
- YO-YO: Copy. I've got Talbot,
but we don't have much
in the way of firepower.
We've got you.
Heading your way.
Copy that.
SIMMONS: Yeah, we copy, as well,
but we may have a bit of
a logistics issue in the lab.
I don't think the Gravitonium
can take the stairs.
♪♪
Deke thinks he can get
one of the elevators moving.
Okay, brilliant.
Yeah, and, uh,
just so everybody's aware,
I think these guys have tech
that can shut down electricity,
like, uh, an EMP,
so flashlights, ICERs...
walkies... they'll be useless.
We need to see these things
if we're gonna stop them.
Fire would work.
Just... Just try and find
something combustible.
Then let's light 'em up.
I always wanted to say that.
♪♪
[Electricity crackles]
They're here.
♪♪
- That's our exit. We're cut off.
- Oh, come on.
We can fight these Remorons.
Get these cuffs off. I can fix this.
Coulson wants you safe,
which means I do, too.
Come on.
♪♪
I can't be stuck in here again.
I can't be stuck in here again. I-I...
There's so much I haven't seen.
I haven't seen the ocean.
I-I haven't seen the Great Wall.
I-I haven't seen Orlando.
What happened to your multiverse?
Thought you were everywhere all at once?
Shut up!
This is insane.
I mean, it's a miracle
you survived all that
- with just one scar?
- Yeah.
You tell everyone that story?
I don't think they care.
Piper, ICERs won't work.
So no modern weapons,
but yes to '70s-era camping equipment?
'Fraid so.
[Door opens in distance]
[Guns cock]
♪♪
[Electricity crackles]
[Breathing heavily]
We stalled them.
They cut off our way to Control.
We had nowhere else to go.
FITZ: Jemma, do you copy?
Yeah, Fitz, I think we're pinned down.
We're going to have to
make our own stand here.
They'll be coming for the Gravitonium.
I know.
♪♪
Sorry, Jemma. I never should've
left your side.
Wait. Deke... has he
blinked out of existence?
♪♪
No, he's still here.
SIMMONS: Then we're good.
You heard him...
they're coming after us.
Okay.
Davis, Piper, we're on point.
Simmons, you stay here
and defend the lab
and, if it comes to it, the Gravitonium.
What about me? Take the cuffs off.
I can fix this.
You just stay back.
Okay.
♪♪
Looks like you and I
are the last line of defense.
♪♪
Thought you might need an escort.
I think we can handle ourselves.
[Electricity crackling]
♪♪
Actually, it was a nice gesture.
Go.
♪♪
Go!
[Machine-gun fire]
I can't see anything! We need recon!
I just did.
I couldn't see them, but I could
feel them all around me.
We're outnumbered.
Stay behind me. I can't be killed.
Well, that makes two of you.
♪♪
DAVIS: There's too many of them!
Hold on as long as you can!
MAY: Bar the doors... all of them.
COULSON: Simmons, Yo-Yo, do you read?
Do not proceed to Control.
We are surrounded.
I repeat, we are surround...
[Static]
Be careful. Stay back.
This is the last line.
Here. Draw a line.
Take a stand.
Hold the line.
Last line. This is the last li...
♪♪
I can fix this.
Talbot.
♪♪
[Handcuffs click]
[Energy whirring]
♪♪
[Talbot screaming]
A light cocktail
of potassium, glycerin...
- and a dash of sugar.
- [Glass shatters]
♪♪
Got it.
Don't worry, Gramps.
If they want the Gravitonium,
they're gonna go through me.
Deke...
♪♪
Whatever happens next...
never call me "gramps" again.
[Glass shatters]
Doubt that this will work
without electricity.
♪♪
Coulson.
Really?
I can... Are you serious?
♪♪
[Glass shatters]
Coulson?
♪♪
Sir?
I don't think the ammo's
gonna get here in time.
[Pounding on door]
[Gun cocks]
Okay, people, this is it.
♪♪
[Pounding on door]
Here we go.
If you need a gun,
you'll take one, right?
Here... take this one.
♪♪
[Pounding on door]
- They're everywhere, just like I said!
- Just hold steady!
[Pounding on door]
♪♪
[Pounding stops]
[Metal clanging]
♪♪
[Growling]
[Gunfire]
♪♪
We don't have enough ammo
to hold them off!
[Grunting]
♪♪
They're coming from all sides!
[Gunfire]
♪♪
Damn it! They jumped in behind us!
They're at the lab!
[Gunfire]
Simmons, can you read me?!
Simmons!
- Oh, something's wrong.
- No, nobody can reach anybody.
It doesn't mean that she's...
♪♪
What was that?
[Screams]
♪♪
[Electricity crackles]
[Gunfire]
- I'm out!
- Me, too!
Look, May, this probably isn't
the best time...
It's not!
♪♪
Bullets didn't do much
to these guys anyway.
♪♪
[All grunting]
[Grunting]
♪♪
[Groans]
[Bones cracking]
♪♪
[Electricity crackles]
Simmons.
[Grunts]
You okay?
Where's Talbot?
♪♪
I told you I could fix this.
[Rumbling]
♪♪
[Electricity crackles, power whirring]
Citizens of the Lighthouse,
I bring you excellent news.
The outer atmosphere shows
no signs of contamination.
Congratulations.
You have survived
the nuclear apocalypse.
The planet is safe again.
[Crickets chirping]
♪♪
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com