Coulson: Previously on
"Marvel's Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
She's the Destroyer.
[Gasps]
Ruby! No!
That girl was a ticking bomb.
You let your emotions
get the best of you.
We all have blood on our hands.
Why am I being singled out?
That's not what we do here.
Thinks he found something
connected to the Deathlok program.
- It could keep Coulson alive.
- Tony: He called it Centipede serum.
Garrett's cocktail had an
extra healing component.
All I got was the name of
some place where they found it.
And I can't find it on any map.
That's 'cause it's not a place.
♪♪
Qovas: I'm here
for what was promised ...
the Gravitonium.
I can fix this.
[Screaming]
♪♪
I told you I could fix this.
[Rumbling]
♪♪
5x20 - The One Who Will Save Us All
Uh, Glenn...
Chin up.
Almost there.
♪♪
Still no word
from our forces below?
- No, commander.
- Then ready the missiles.
Something has entered
our docking station.
- A terran ship?
- The object appears to be human.
♪♪
You are now prisoners
of the Remorath.
So, what's our play?
Now you and I are gonna show
these E.T.s who's boss.
Don't worry.
I can fix this.
I really wish you'd stop saying that.
♪♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
♪♪
Okay, so how much
Gravitonium did Talbot use?
- All of it.
- Well, maybe it's not so bad.
I mean, he did just annihilate
a bunch of Remorath warlords.
But the side effects
of Gravitonium are catastrophic.
- Ruby absorbed just a fraction...
- And it drove her completely insane.
Yeah, well, she wasn't
all that stable before.
- Neither was Talbot.
- With his previous brain injury,
I feel that Talbot
will almost certainly
- suffer a major psychotic break.
- [Sighs] We need to find them.
The Lighthouse only just
came back online.
It could be hours before all
systems are fully functional.
Where's Mack?
Went to make sure
the threat's been neutralized.
♪♪
[Remorath grunting]
Oh, not this again.
[Gunshots]
♪♪
[Gun clicks]
[Grunts]
♪♪
[Groans]
Mack, no!
We need it alive.
This thing is our only chance
to find out what Coulson
and Talbot are up against.
♪♪
[Grunts]
Pretty sure we just left
Earth's atmosphere.
Doesn't matter what galaxy
they try and run and hide in.
We're gonna show them
who's in charge.
I feel like we're seeing this
adventure a little differently.
- Gravitonium, why?
- 'Cause I'm our last hope.
- What about the voices?
- Bunch of dead losers raising a ruckus.
Turns out, all they needed was
a general to get them in line.
Wish I found that more reassuring.
I'm a little worried
about you, Glenn.
It takes most people years
to get a handle on their powers.
You skipped the tutorial,
went straight to big-boss level.
You got to quit worrying, Phil.
I'm feeling fine ... tip-top.
Even brought
my best wingman with me.
What these alien scumbags
didn't count on
is squaring off against
the two best military minds
- the world has to offer.
- No, they most certainly did not.
♪♪
You dare to approach my ship.
How about letting your wingman
take point on this?
♪♪
We're here to negotiate
a deal for Earth.
The Confederacy already has a deal ...
with Hydra.
Thing is,
Hydra doesn't really speak
for all of humanity ...
or any of it.
Hydra has spent years
kneeling before me,
groveling at my feet, and only
then did I offer assistance.
Yet you sneak aboard my ship
and have the arrogance
to make demands.
♪♪
I think
there's a misunderstanding.
♪♪
- You see, this is my ship.
- Easy, buddy.
- Your impudent tone is only go...
- I said this is my ship!
[Grunts]
[Rumbling]
♪♪
Seems like you got
the weight of the world
on your shoulders there, pal.
[Rumbling continues]
♪♪
That's better.
Now... you.
Kneel.
♪♪
I'm not sure that's the best
negotiating tactic.
I said kneel before me!
♪♪
That's pretty good teamwork, Phil.
Hey, I heard about today.
You okay?
Yeah, it's not
the first creepy crawler
I've had to go
toe-to-toe with.
♪♪
No, I'm good.
[sighs] Mack.
Um, they're waiting for me.
♪♪
- How many are on that ship?
- He give us any leads?
Just promises to disembowel us.
The Confederacy has stood
more than 1,000 years.
They will seek vengeance,
making slaves of you all.
Really wish we could happen upon
some non-slave-trading aliens.
Any idea why this one
is more rabid than the rest?
It probably has something to do
with this.
I'm pretty sure this is
the same stuff Kasius took.
Must give them
some sort of energy boost.
You are not worthy
of holding the Odium.
- 'Course it would have a dumb name.
- What the hell's that stuff do?
The Odium
gives the power of the gods
- to those in final battle.
- First of all, there's only one God.
It is glory
through the spilling of blood,
the taste of your enemy's pain.
[Grunting]
♪♪
And God definitely doesn't
want you drinking that garbage.
- Any way to know how it works?
- Not without opening him up.
♪♪
I'll get right to it.
Well, [Chuckles]
not bad for a day's work.
Got to admit, I'm impressed,
though the kneeling may have
been a little over-the-top.
♪♪
Do not contradict me, Phil.
This is war.
First we establish dominance,
then we dictate terms, yeah?
Just want to make sure
we're on the same page.
Maybe now's the time
to talk big picture.
- I'm gonna save the world.
- From whom?
The Confederacy decides
what you will and will not do.
- It will not stand idly by while you ...
- Stand?
Gee, I don't see any
Confederate members standing.
Y-You ... Phil,
you see anybody standing?
Hydra was never this foolish.
- Yeah, well, where's Hydra now?
- Your ignorance astounds.
♪♪
That's how they found us.
- Hale.
- Take me to her.
♪♪
[Door closes]
You here as a prisoner?
♪♪
- I sold out your team.
- Yeah.
Well, it was the only option I had.
The Confederacy was done waiting
for Gravitonium, and...
...without Ruby...
I'm sorry for your loss.
♪♪
I've been angry for so long.
You know,
every time I got passed over,
ignored, talked down to,
I just swallowed it.
I told myself
I'd make it better for Ruby,
but that anger just...
was just always there, the hatred.
In the end, all I did was
carry out Hydra's agenda.
I never even took a breath,
stop to think about the...
the gift that life had given me.
♪♪
[Sighs]
I failed her.
Ruby died for nothing,
and it was all my fault.
♪♪
We could use your help.
[Sighs]
♪♪
- I got nothing left to give.
- You'd be surprised.
Seems there's been
a development
with your
Destroyer of Worlds project.
Turns out, it's a go.
♪♪
Daisy Johnson
went into the machine?
Actually, it was someone
a little more out of the box.
♪♪
I think it's time
you tell me about
the rest of your compadres.
I would rather die
than betray the Confederacy.
♪♪
There are six seats ...
Kallusians, Rajaks,
Astrans all
count themselves members,
obviously, the Remoraths,
- and there are two other warrior clans.
- You?
You dragged me away
from my family,
kept me in a hole for six months,
and messed with my head.
Why should I believe a single
word coming out of your mouth?
You have every right to be upset,
but the Confederacy's still out there.
She's the only one
who knows how they operate.
Look,
what I did to you was wrong,
but it was all
to bring us to this moment.
Humankind is
in terrible danger, and you ...
you're the weapon
that I was trying to build.
You're the only one
that can save us all.
♪♪
What was Hydra's arrangement
with the Confederacy?
To protect the Earth
from being attacked.
- In exchange for what?
- Resources.
♪♪
Inhumans and Gravitonium above all.
- Why Gravitonium?
- Because its power is unlimited.
It can bend space,
build empires, and destroy them.
Couldn't you just find a fun
game on your phone instead?
Hale: Look, we need to renegotiate
our deal with the Confederacy.
I think maybe it's time
we started shaking some hands.
Qovas: Impossible. The
Confederacy gathering is sacred,
a ceremony dating back
over five of your centuries.
Well, as a military man,
I'd hate to buck tradition.
♪♪
So why don't you bring me up
to speed on protocol?
Even if the Confederacy
were to grant you an audience,
you have nothing to offer.
♪♪
But if it's Gravitonium your
friends want, there he is.
Fitz: This is an outright disaster.
♪♪
Could take hours to rewire this
antiquated system, and by then,
who knows what cosmos
the Remorath will escape to.
♪♪
Yeah. Fixing old electronics
was kind of my thing
back in the day in the future.
♪♪
- What are ... What are you doing?
- What? It's a thing.
It's a thing
that people do to celebrate.
Not cool people.
Come on, man.
- You're better than that..
- Okay.
♪♪
[Sighs]
Just took Talbot flying out of
here like some sort of a wizard
in order to be able
to breathe fresh air again.
Well, being a S.H.I.E.L.D. Agent
has its risks.
Yeah, but that's just it.
I'm not a S.H.I.E.L.D. Agent.
But for some reason, I'm still
hanging around this rusty drainpipe.
Well, you do have family here.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, I don't think it's that.
♪♪
Oh, well, don't get me wrong.
You guys are great ...
totally not disappointments at all.
Daisy: Lighthouse,
is anyone there? Over.
Repeat. Lighthouse,
this is Daisy Johnson.
Does anyone copy?
Yeah, uh, we're here, Daisy. Sorry.
We just had
some technical difficulties.
Deke, thank God you're there. I've been
trying to get through for 30 minutes.
I'm flying in.
What's wrong?
We were under attack.
Where were you?
May had me drop off
Polly and Robin.
Lie. I know that's not all.
I'm not having this conversation
right now, Yo-Yo.
- Coulson's missing.
- Coulson's missing because of you.
After all your finger-wagging,
the same rules don't apply to you?
You are the last person who should
be giving a lecture right now.
♪♪
What's in the bag? Is that
what you abandoned us for?
It's none of your business.
♪♪
What's wrong with y...
[Both grunting]
♪♪
We needed you.
People died.
[Grunts]
Don't put that on me.
♪♪
[Rumbling] Oh, you
want to use powers now?
♪♪
Then I definitely win.
[Grunts]
♪♪
[Gunshot]
- You done?
- May.
Satellite just picked up an object
outside of Earth's atmosphere.
Piper believes
it's the Remorath ship.
When do we leave?
As soon as the artificial
gravity's installed in the Zephyr.
♪♪
She's gonna get everyone killed.
We're going to help Coulson.
Either find a way to pitch in or
don't be here when we get back.
♪♪
Talbot: I appreciate the trim,
but feels like a lot of
pomp and circumstance to me.
We need allies for whatever war
is coming to Earth.
- Diplomacy is key.
- Maybe I should come along,
help navigate any choppy waters.
Best not to rock the boat.
These snowflakes seem
awfully precious about decorum.
- I think I'll just take the alien.
- Okay, but remember, tread lightly.
- Try and get feel for the ...
- I already told you I can fix this.
♪♪
How do I look?
Pretty cool, actually.
I can probably get the boys to
rustle you up one if you want.
I'm good.
Not much of a robes guy.
I'm leaving this man in charge.
Anybody here disobeys an order,
you'll suffer the same pretzel
logic your friend did earlier.
All right, Chuckles, let's hit it.
♪♪
[Electricity crackling]
[Sighs]
The six all stand present.
Let us unite under the banner
of one true Confederacy.
Qovas, who is this intruder?
This man hails from Earth.
He has come...
to renegotiate
terms of their protection.
The terms have already been set.
Why would we even entertain
such derangement?
Because...
you guys have been dealing with
a bunch of weak amateurs.
It's time you met
Earth's mightiest hero...
me.
♪♪
[Daisy sighs]
[Knock on door]
- What's in the bag?
- My mom.
Oh.
I heard about
your little dust up.
I just wanted to make sure
you're all right.
I've been better.
It's like the universe
keeps reminding me
that I should never
have come back from the future.
Also, some creep put a
bunch of lemons on my bed
as some weird sort of... prank.
♪♪
[Chuckles]
Sounds like classic Fitz.
Look, I, um ...
I feel like
you're exactly where
you're supposed to be.
I, on the other hand, I ...
I lived in the Lighthouse
my entire life,
only to time travel into the
past and still spend every
single day of my life inside
the freaking Lighthouse. So...
it's like,
even without Kasius around,
this place just has this leash
that keeps pulling me back in.
Well, I'm glad you stuck around,
even if it's a little crazy.
♪♪
W-Well,
maybe it's not that crazy.
♪♪
I-I-I've been wanting
to tell you something
since we've gotten,
you know, I don't want
to say closer, but ...
[Scoffs]
You really don't.
Everyone who gets close
to me ends up dying.
Me, too.
And that's why I feel like
we have so much in common.
- My mom.
- I-I know, and ... and ...
- Lincoln.
- Who's Lincoln?
Uh, Lincoln Campbell.
He...
He was the first Inhuman
that I became close with.
Fought at our side, and he ...
he died.
♪♪
He died for me, really.
Right when
we were getting going,
or, you know, getting good.
It sounds like you were really
in love with this guy.
♪♪
Kind of still am.
Which is why
I-I can't lose someone else,
and Coulson means more to me
than anyone.
- And if he goes ...
- No, no, no, no.
W-We'll ... we're gonna find
a way to save him.
♪♪
Sorry. You ... You were
gonna tell me something.
♪♪
Yeah, Fitz-Simmons...
are my grandparents.
What?
- Wait, what?
- I know.
- Are you serious?
- Mm-hmm.
Do they know?
Yeah, yeah, cat's totally
out of the food sack.
Oh, my God.
That makes so much sense.
You and Fitz are both so...
You're such special people.
[Chuckles] Well, good.
I ... I was worried
that was gonna make
things weird between us.
Wait, why would it
make things weird?
♪♪
No reason.
[Chuckles]
♪♪
Estella: This man
is clearly a charlatan.
No mortal being can wield
the power of Gravitonium,
especially not some...
human.
I submit we strip him to rags,
then put him to auction.
That would be most unwise, Estella.
He had somehow harness
Gravitonium within himself,
Even so, he has no bearing.
This man is not of the Confederacy,
- he has no business here.
- Well, then, maybe it's time
you made me a part of
your little secret society.
Crixon: Impossible.
For centuries, the Confederacy
has had but six members.
To add another
would desecrate the Order.
[Chuckles] This is like a
room full of... Democrats.
You got your rules
and your regulations...
Who's really in charge here?
Estella: This is a Confederacy.
All voices are equal.
Though...
Crixon is often considered
the most wise amongst us.
♪♪
The fact remains,
there is simply no place
for a human amongst us.
Your mistake is thinking
I'm still human.
♪♪
[Grunting]
[Rumbling]
[Grunting continues]
♪♪
[Chuckles]
[Exhales sharply]
Well...
♪♪
looks like there's a spot
for me here after all.
♪♪
Good job
getting this assembled.
- That it?
- Yeah.
♪♪
[Whirring]
[Tablet beeps]
♪♪
Guess we just built
S.H.I.E.L.D.'s first spaceship.
Mack.
I just wanted to apologize for...
locking you up... before.
Really wasn't my idea.
- I actually had ...
- You went along with it.
♪♪
Yeah, well, we were trying
to get ahead of the problem.
♪♪
By having Yo-Yo execute a kid?
[Sighs]
Things got messy,
but, I mean,
it was the only way that Y-Yo...
When does killing
become the only way?
We're S.H.I.E.L.D.
Aren't we supposed to be
better than that?
None of this would've happened
if you would've just said
this invincible nonsense
wasn't real.
But instead you and Simmons
lit the match,
and now Yo-Yo's responsible
for a girl's death.
I'm sorry, Mack.
I really am.
But it's not that simple.
Simple is how
you live a good life.
Not with your theories
or prophecies.
It's following
the Good Word
and doing the right thing
every time,
- simple as that.
- No.
Not always,
'cause there are lots of
instances in history where ...
where it was necessary
to sacrifice the few
in order to save the lives of many.
♪♪
'Course you'd say that.
Ruby was dangerous
and it got complicated
and that is just the way it was.
So I'm sorry if that doesn't fit
whatever narrative
that you've built for yourself.
You need
to look inside yourself
and figure out what kind
of man you want to be.
'Cause lately,
what you've been,
it needs fixing.
♪♪
[Footsteps approach]
What happened there?
This Remorath
ingested a substance
that stimulated
every single cell in its body.
And, what, its heart exploded?
- Rather macabre, isn't it?
- Just you wait.
♪♪
Where did you get that?
What matters is that we might
be able to save Coulson
by combining that
with my... mom's DNA.
Oh, Daisy.
This feels like
we may be crossing a line.
Then we cross it. Are you just
willing to let Coulson die?
It's not that simple.
There are moral implications.
This isn't a morality debate.
It's just a question.
Are you willing to let Coulson die?
Yes or no?
- No.
- Good. Then get to work.
This is your top priority.
♪♪
- We space ready?
- Looks like we're about to find out.
You coming with?
Yeah, I just need
to get out of the Lighthouse.
Davis: So you're going on a space
mission to a hostile alien ship?
Yeah, well, I don't have
that many options.
This is Zephyr One.
We are all systems go.
Piper: Roger that, Zephyr.
You are clear for takeoff.
♪♪
You were right to bring
this man here, Qovas,
for truly he stands a giant.
As always, you see wisdom
while the others cower in fear.
A strength of our warrior breeding.
I'm sorry, partner.
I didn't get your name earlier.
No apology necessary.
The honor is mine.
I am the firstborn Taryan,
- master of the house Kasius.
- Kasius.
Well, that certainly has a ring.
The way you handled yourself
today was quite admirable.
Though I fear your Earth faces
a far more pressing threat
than anything posed
by our Confederacy.
Is this the attack Qovas
warned might be coming?
It shall be the end of your planet.
That's why Hale
had a deal with the Confederacy
to fight beside us.
The Confederacy never intended
to honor this agreement,
nor could it even if it so desired.
It was merely a deception
to extort the resources
from your planet
before time ran out,
- which now it has.
- What are you saying?
Thanos and his forces have begun
an assault on your world,
- even as we speak.
- Well, then, I've got to get down there
with the Avengers
and take on this... Thanos.
Thanos' strength is unrivaled.
You will lose
even with your powerful
friends fighting alongside you.
♪♪
Though perhaps...
there might still be a way.
♪♪
Astronauts say the view of Earth
from space changes you.
It's why I always
wanted to be one.
Malick had Project Distant Star
running inside NASA.
Why didn't you go work for him?
Leadership had other plans for me.
[sighs]
♪♪
Really rolled the dice letting
Talbot go out on his own.
Not to mention we have no
way out if things go sideways.
Artillery, I'm guessing?
Probably have
enough firepower there
to incinerate your entire base.
[Whirring]
♪♪
Seems the situation
is worse than we feared.
The Earth is under attack
by an alien named Thanos.
What about the Confederacy?
Did they agree to help us?
More bark than bite.
I'm afraid
we're on our own, General.
- We have to get back.
- And do what exactly?
The only option left ...
make me invincible.
- Excuse me?
- I struck up a conversation
with this guy from the Confederacy.
He tells me there's untapped
deposits of Gravitonium
under the Earth's surface.
And you want to get it out
and power yourself up more.
Well, that way, I can handle
any threat the Earth faces.
I can be... the shield.
Can we just talk about this
for a second?
No, you don't get to call
a time-out, Phil.
Our very way of life
is under threat.
Which we will find a way to defeat.
But Gravitonium?
It's too dangerous.
You could lose control.
I've never been more in control.
You know, it is just like you
to second-guess me.
♪♪
Or is it now that you've seen
Gravitonium's power,
you want it all for yourself?
That's not what's happening,
and you know it.
Do I? How many times
have we worked together
only for me later to find out
you weren't being above-board?
Do you trust
this Confederacy member
who told you about
the Gravitonium?
Yeah, real straight shooter
named Kasius.
- Said he has two sons of his own.
- Did you say Kasius?
Glenn, you're being played.
You can't trust him.
The hell is wrong with you, Phil?
First you question my capacity
to handle myself
and then it's our allies,
who you begged me to make.
I know it sounds crazy,
but the alien running Earth
in the future was a Kasius.
He's our enemy.
Kasius is the most noble family
in the Confederacy.
This man is clearly lying.
So what?
Is this another angle
you're playing, Phil?
- Glenn ...
- We are at war ...
a war we will surely lose
if I am not the most powerful
being in the universe.
No, there's got to be another way.
- We can use this ship and attack.
- This is not a debate!
♪♪
I'm in charge here.
You're either with me
or against me.
- Obviously, I'm with you.
- Then kneel.
♪♪
- What?
- I'm Earth's last hope, Phil,
its true protector,
the one who can save us all.
Now, either you accept that...
[Rumbling]
♪♪
[Grunts]
[Grunting]
♪♪
...or suffer the consequences.
[panting]
Kneel.
♪♪
[Sighs]
[Inhales deeply]
Artificial gravity engaged.
Approaching outer atmosphere.
Prepare for Vertical Burn.
Roger that.
Vertical Burn is a go.
♪♪
[Grunting]
Zephyr press to MECO.
Thrusters at full.
Zephyr, your shut-down plan
is nominal.
I probably should've
talked you out of this.
What?
No, this is great.
I'm going to space ... again.
♪♪
Thanks for coming along.
[Davis breathing heavily]
We're approaching
the Kármán line.
Nominal MECO, Main Thruster
is no longer required.
Copy, Zephyr ... Nominal MECO,
Main Thruster no longer required.
Prepare to be the first
S.H.I.E.L.D. team in space.
In this timeline, maybe.
♪♪
May: Looks like we did it, Control.
Piper: Roger that, Zephyr.
Good work, you guys.
Mack: Time to
turn on cloaking.
Won't be long till you reach the ship.
Copy that.
♪♪
- Looks like the Zephyr's in space.
- 'Cause of your design.
♪♪
I know you'd rather be
up in Control right now.
No, it's probably best
that I'm not.
♪♪
So, the Centipede Formula
is functioning as what?
Some sort of catalyst
to unleash Jiaying's
regenerative properties?
That's the hope.
[Sighs]
You really think
this is a good idea?
[Sighs]
What I think is,
the less we talk about it, the better.
Now, unzip that duffel
and get me a viable sample.
♪♪
Davis: Approaching enemy ship.
No signs of resistance yet.
♪♪
That is one big ship.
Just remember,
the minute the Zephyr docks,
cloaking won't matter.
You need to be ready to move.
♪♪
Strike team in position.
Quinn's team originally
found Gravitonium
at the bottom of one of his mines.
- How did you know that?
- He just told me.
Sensors indicate an unseen
object has breached our hull.
- How is that possible?
- Cloaking.
♪♪
What is S.H.I.E.L.D. doing here?
- I guess providing backup.
- This is mutiny.
You made contact behind my back?
- That's not true.
- They're here to do what, take my ship?
- You've got this all wrong.
- You're a liar! You're a liar!
♪♪
Did you have any part in this?
I told Coulson not to do it.
- He wouldn't listen to me.
- Also not true.
♪♪
Find the intruders and take them out.
They're here to help.
What are you doing?
♪♪
Glenn, don't do this.
You have betrayed me
for the last time, Phil.
Whatever happens next is on you.
♪♪
[Rumbling]
It's a start.
♪♪
S.H.I.E.L.D. is not your enemy.
All these years,
double-crossing me.
I should've known better.
[Rumbling]
♪♪
- You quake and Coulson dies.
- What are you doing?
S.H.I.E.L.D. isn't welcome here.
This is my ship.
This is an alien ship.
We're here to rescue you.
Rescue me?
I'm the one that's gonna save us.
Then put Coulson down,
and we can talk about that.
Agent Johnson, always in
the center of the storm.
Maybe that's because
you're the problem.
If I'm the one you want, fine,
I won't resist,
but first you have to
put Coulson down.
You and I both know
you can't be trusted.
I trust her.
♪♪
Why would you trust Quake?
Because she kept her word.
When Ruby was infected
with Gravitonium,
she tried to help.
Infected?
Ruby was weak.
Gravitonium wasn't intended
for some itty-bitty little girl.
It was meant for a hero
strong enough to handle it.
You need to take a deep breath
and calm your mind, Glenn.
♪♪
[Rumbling]
You know what's best.
♪♪
It's best if you comply.
Compliance will be rewarded.
♪♪
That's right.
And so will your betrayal.
♪♪
[Rumbling]
[Grunts]
♪♪
Go ahead.
Fire that weapon, Agent May,
and Coulson dies just like Hale.
♪♪
Do you surrender, Agent May?
What should we do with them?
♪♪
They're prisoners of war.
Treat them accordingly.
It didn't have to be like this.
You were always
the enemy, Phil.
Only now I have
the clarity of mind to see it.
♪♪
Coulson: We'll return in a moment.
The Earth is no longer
a hidden blue gem.
It belongs to another now.
♪♪
And yet it still has gifts to give.
So I look forward
to taking mine home.
♪♪
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~