Previously on "Marvel's Agents Of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
Phil Coulson is dying.
Can we cure this?
The tissue is already dead.
There is no cure for that.
Ruby, when they resurface, I'll put an end to all of this.
This entire S.H.I.E.L.D. chapter will be over.
Your work is incomplete,
At least the beacon will do what it's supposed to do.
I think that ?when the monoliths exploded,
they tore open a fear dimension.
And I was hoping ?there was enough Gravitonium
to stitch together the tear in space-time.
Deke Shaw could possibly be an LMD.
I ran a genetic profile to see if he was
biologically linked to anyone.
And it came up with a match?
No. ?
It came up with two.
Have you heard of Thorazine, Alex?
I only mentioned it
because that's what ‭they're proposing for you --
a high dose, much more aggressive treatment
than what you're taking in the mornings now.
I'm the one holding them back, because I feel for you.
I don't think that ‭you are a violent person.
A few outbursts don't define you.
But you need to open up about the trauma that led you here,
starting with your father's abuse,
and then torture ‭at the hands of Mr. Ward,
and then S.H.I.E.L.D.
I remember everything.
That's a start.
But we need to drill down on how that makes you feel,
show them some improvement
so they don't drug you
to the point where thoughts are hard to come by, okay?
So, we can start anywhere.
April.
Okay. What happened in April?
April...
your daughter.
Just turned 3.
I never spoke about --
Six weeks ago, during our Tuesday session, it was raining.
You always prop the window open with a pen.
Your wife called, ‭and you answered after one ring.
Tight leash, huh?
You stepped outside to talk,
but the door's not as thick as you think.
April had a fever -- 103.2.
All those kids at the parties, a lot of germs.
You said you'd be home early.
513 Elm Drive, right?
You know where I live?
You should really be more careful.
You never know what someone might do with that information.
I told you -- I remember everything.
I'd like ‭that Thorazine now, please.
‭Everything is stabilizing -- back in normal range.
Bit of good news.
How's the pain?
Nothing I can't handle. Thank you.
Well, how's this? You okay?
- It's fine. - Good. Okay.
Well you need to stay warm.
can I get you anything to eat?
Mack, enough.
Seriously, if I had arms, I would strangle you right now.
How's the patient?
- Cranky. - How are you feeling?
The same way I was feeling
before you knew ‭anything was wrong with me.
Thank you for asking, but, please, stop asking.
Fitz is gonna do the best prosthetics work
he's ever done for you,
but it may take some time.
We don't have the materials he needs here,
but we're gonna find a way to get them.
In the meantime, I need you to focus on resting and healing.
Sitting still isn't my strong suit.
I know, but he'll make it worth the wait.
See?
People can't even tell the difference.
And, honestly, this one's way more fun.
- He's always adding - Does it feel the same?
Actually, no.
It doesn't feel at all, but you get used to it.
How are you gonna feel about dating someone with robo-parts?
Those aren't the parts that matter.
Mack!
What? Oh, no, come on. That's not what I meant.
What I meant was that the thing I hate about robots
is that they have no heart, no soul --
those are the parts that matter.
Nice save.
And sweet.
Okay. You can be annoying again.
Well, it's my turn now. Time to break up this party.
You need rest.
I need a beer.
I'll see what I can do about that.
In the meantime, you listen to the doc, all right?
We need to get out of here
and get Fitz what he needs to fix her.
I know, Mack, but it's one of many pressing concerns.
I was just coming to see you.
Tidings of comfort and joy?
Warnings of doom and gloom.
The, uh -- The Gravitonium device that we used
to seal the rift is barely strong enough.
It's duct tape on the Hoover Dam. It's not gonna hold.
How much time before the dam starts leaking?
Well, uh, it's hard to calculate that precisely,
but, based on the increased frequency of transit,
electromagnetic waves,
I'd say that our days were numbered.
Sorry. That was insensitive.
No, it wasn't. It's part of life. We're all gonna die.
Right now, we need to make sure it doesn't happen
to the entire planet all at once.
So, we need more Gravitonium
to seal the rift for good, right?
Yeah, but that's something we haven't seen
on this side of the future in a long time.
Sir...
I really think that we should have everybody on this.
Me too.
Let's not forget about Yo-Yo.
She can't help until we help her.
Daisy's hoping we can tackle both problems with one solution.
Cybertek.
The last time anyone saw Gravitonium in this time line
was at Cybertek's lab,
which happens to be the same company that built Deathlok's leg.
- Now we're talking. - Cybertek was dissolved.
Quinn's vanished. Raina's dead.
Gravitonium is still M.I.A.
Yeah, but we found ‭the names of the scientists
who worked under Ian Quinn, so...
Who's Ian Quinn?
Rich guy, bad guy.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm not part of the club?
I'm sorry. ‭I'll just go get my things,
and I'll go grab a cheeseburger.
Have a seat, Deke. I invited him.
He's seen more Gravitonium than any of us.
He may have some insight that we don't.
Okay. So, this is Quinn's Gravitonium guy,
Dr. Joseph Getty.
Also dead. We chased that lead.
Right, but here's where it gets interesting --
all of Cybertek's scientists are now dead, within the past two years,
and all of their death certificates were signed by one man...
Murray Jacobson.
What? So, you think it's a cover-up? They're still alive?
Yeah, it smells like it,
but this photo's all I could find on him.
You ran facial recognition?
I did, and I found his mug
associated with multiple aliases,
the most recent being Lewis Casalino,
a real-estate agent in Baton Rouge.
We need to talk to him.
So...we're going outside?
Yeah, they're kind of sparing no expense looking for you guys.
We'll leave under cover of night.
It's a risk we have to take.
If he can help us find Dr. Getty,
we may get a lead on Gravitonium.
Yeah. I'm going with you.
I thought you grounded yourself.
Yeah, I can't really destroy the world without my powers, so...
I can take care of myself.
I know. ‭I just want some fresh air.
Right. Well...fresh air for all of us.
- Have a seat, Deke. - Okay.
I need you to stay here.
See if you can help Fitz.
What? N-No. Come on.
I'm -- I'm not a babysitter.
Do you have any idea how high my IQ is?
Actually, neither do I.
Nobody actually cared about that in the future.
Intelligence was measured by how long you could survive.
Then be smart and stay here.
Hello.
What is this place?
Where are we?!
Lewis Casalino?
AKA Murray Jacobson, William Pratt,
Gene Kline, Marion Cobretti.
He's armed, ‭and he's coming your way.
Show yourself, or I'll drop you.
Drop the gun. We just want to talk.
You heard him -- drop the gun.
Listen, ladycakes,
I take orders from two people -- no one and not you.
Candy Man?
Mack Hammer?
Well, I'll be damned.
Do I owe you money?
Hey, it's probably the other way around, brother.
Oh, it's good to see you.
Good to see you.
There he is -- Tony "Candy Man" Caine.
We were roommates ‭freshman year at the Academy.
Why'd they call you "Candy Man"?
Well, Tony was the kind of guy who could get you anything --
you know, fake I.D.S,
backstage passes, test answers.
What did I get for all my troubles?
Booted from the Academy.
Well, you also never went to class.
Oh, yeah, well, I really wasn't a books-and-test kind of guy.
That was Mack -- never missed a class, never broke a rule.
They called us the Saint and the Sinner.
Wait. Could we get back to "Mack Hammer," please?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
He made the mistake of telling us
that he was obsessed with MC Hammer in high school.
Okay.
Wait. Where's your picture?
‭- Don't -- - ‭Oh, my, my.
- There he is. That's it. - You can't unsee that, Mack.
All right, this does not leave the plane.
All right, guys, guys, I'm guessing you didn't track me down
to relive good memories and awesome haircuts.
You're right.
We're looking ‭for a Cybertek scientist
named Joseph Getty.
And why would I know him?
You signed his death certificate.
If he's still alive, he may have valuable information for us.
He could help us keep the world
from shattering into a billion pieces.
Okay.
You guys ever hear of Project Paperclip?
Secret program ‭to recruit Nazi scientists
after World War II.
Yeah, and the exact same thing happened with Hydra
for those worthy of a second chance.
And it was my job to give them new identities,
new lives, erase the old ones.
So, you know where he is.
We need to talk to him, Tony.
Well, if the Mack Hammer's willing to break the rules,
this has got to be bad.
Yeah, doomsday bad.
Following the rules is no longer an option.
Look what I found in storage.
Baseball, right?
Did everybody have really big hands?
'Cause this is crazy.
There's another one if you want to play.
I'm monitoring ‭a highly volatile situation.
Well, yeah, I'm trying to help.
You don't have to be such a cranky, old man about it.
If you're stuck on a problem, you should take a break.
My mom used to tell me
about this guy named Albert Einstein.
He says that play is the highest form of research.
I'm not gonna play catch with you.
I've got stuff to... Okay?
Well, why don't I stay here
and stare at the numbers for a little while?
You can go visit Mrs. Fitz.
You guys just got married. All the grown-ups are gone.
I bet she's just dying for a little post-wedding yee-haw.
Okay, do you know what, Einstein? You're right.
I need a break, so let's play ball.
Let's play ball. Come on.
Okay. Toss me the ball, and we'll play fetch.
Ready?
Damn. It's happening again.
We are experiencing another anomaly flare.
If you see something that doesn't belong here,
it's not real.
Kill it by any means necessary.
What happened?
You okay?
I woke up.
I forgot I didn't have arms.
Okay, let's just get you back up there.
Please, leave me alone.
I just want to sit here.
I want to be with Mack forever,
and I want ‭to have children with him.
And you will.
This doesn't change anything.
Look at me.
What I saw, what I heard --
that's all happening.
There's no future but the one I saw.
No, that's not true.
We can change it.
We will change it.
No.
Nothing's gonna change it.
You're different, man.
You hated violence.
Now look at this -- you got this shotgun ax thing.
You're one of America's most wanted.
I mean, it's badass and everything, don't get me wrong,
but, dude, what happened?
There are a lot of dark things going on in this world
that people should never have to see.
I won't let the people I love get hurt by them.
Not anymore.
So, that's why you were asking about the Deathlok program.
I'm sorry, man. It's a dead end.
I know Cybertek coerced a lot of people,
but I'm still not sure how I feel
about a bunch of their scientists
getting clean slates and walking among us.
What if one of them has the key to saving you?
You were hoping Cybertek could solve more than two problems.
I am not gonna be the next John Garrett.
The answer's no.
Okay, just hear me out for a second.
Cybertek had a whole team of people
whose only job was to keep Garrett alive.
What if one of them could do the same for you?
Absolutely not. That's an order.
If there's a chance to save your life, why not try?
Because I already had one unnatural life extension,
and I don't want another.
You both have to accept that.
Not gonna happen.
Not a chance.
He was our shield when we needed it,
and like it or not,
we're gonna be his.
Come on in. Join the party.
Wow. You can talk.
When I feel like it.
What is this place?
A safe house.
Why are you here?
I live here.
Why am I here?
You will get ‭all of your questions answered
when you get them answered.
From who?
Mother.
What?
You still have that scar...
that you got when you were a kid?
How did you know?
We used to play together.
Ruby, right?
I don't remember you.
You hit your head on the kitchen counter.
That's how you got it.
I remember the floor --
Black-and-white checkers.
I was supposed to be watching you, so I got blamed.
My father beat me ‭in front of you and your mother.
I want to see her... now.
Well, this can't be good.
Did they find me?
Do I have to relocate again?
Everything's okay. ‭This isn't an official visit.
I just need you to help me find something.
What?
Gravitonium.
It's okay. ‭He's an old friend of mine.
You can trust him. ‭He's one of the good guys.
I'm with S.H.I.E.L.D.
No, no. They're the bad guys now.
I can't be seen talking to a criminal!
Says the guy who used to work for Hydra.
Listen, he had to work for them.
They were threatening to kill his family.
I'm sorry.
I still regret everything I did for them,
but I'm paying for my sins.
Saving the world will pay for them all.
What do you need to know?
What happened to the Gravitonium?
They put it on a cargo ship, the Principia,
to transport it to a facility in the Pacific, but...
never made it.
Why? What happened?
It sank during a thunderstorm.
If you want Gravitonium,
you're gonna have to reach 5 miles
down into the ocean to get it.
We're looking in an area that they've already searched.
There's nothing there.
I expanded the search range 100 miles in every direction
from the coordinates at which it last made contact.
Bathymetric maps don't show anything.
Sonar doesn't pick up any deviations.
So, maybe they were hijacked by pirates.
He said it went down in a storm.
Did you ever consider he might be lying?
He was Hydra.
Mack believes him.
Keep looking.
Look at all that water.
‭You should get some rest.
You haven't slept all night.
I'm fine. I'm fine. I just --
I don't know where else to look,
and even if we do find it,
I don't know how we salvage it from that depth.
How deep?
5 miles where we're looking.
5 miles?!
Are you serious? What's it like down there?
- Dark. - It's cold.
So, did you guys go visit, like, on holiday?
Do they have hotels, or is that, like --
Okay, do you know what? Just go.
Please, please, just go,
because you are giving me a headache.
Well, I'm sorry that I have never seen an ocean before.
Where I was born,
you guys already blew up the planet,
so thank you very much for your service.
He never stops.
It's like somebody let Scrappy-Doo in here.
You can't be so hard on him.
We both know what it's like
to be pulled into a strange world.
Plus, he has exquisite taste in wedding rings.
Can you believe ‭that we're married...
wife?
I cannot, husband.
Do you think we'll ever get used to it, husband?
No, I do not, wife.
Hey, I was thinking -- we should hyphenate our last name, yeah?
Uh, yeah, of course.
Mr. And Mrs. Simmons-Fitz.
‭Sounds great.
Just rolls right off the tongue.
Yeah, right off.
Let her go...
or they will kill you.
Why am I here?
They wanted to chemically lobotomize you,
so I had you transferred.
Maybe that's what I wanted.
It's good to see you, Werner, after all these years.
It's Alex -- Alex Braun.
I don't want anything to do with my father or his name
or Hydra.
Hydra.
Such a boys' club.
So much testosterone.
If you're not Hydra,
why were you always visiting my father?
Oh, we had overlapping interests back then...
but I hated his guts, if we're being honest.
I can use you, Alex.
I know what you can do,
'cause I've read your S.H.I.E.L.D. File,
your psych evaluations.
I've pieced it all together.
S.H.I.E.L.D. zapped your brain
when you were in the memory enhancer.
Something was bound to happen.
I mean, h-how much do you remember?
What you mean is, how much do I remember
that my father said or did or -- or wrote down?
It's valuable information.
And your father is one of the reasons
that Hydra went off the rails.
See, what I'm building here is something new,
a better future for you -- for you and for Ruby.
Can you help me do that, Alex?
Go to hell.
I am so sorry you feel that way.
Kill me.
I don't care.
I'm not gonna kill you, Alex.
Tomorrow morning, I'll take you wherever it is you want to go.
You're free. Go.
It's my gift to you.
Gain his trust,
his love --
whatever it is you need to do to get inside his head.
We need that information.
Ruby.
Stick to the books this time.
Don't you go off the rails.
Oh, my God.
I've got to meet the chef that invented these.
Deke!
Who's there?
Mom?
There you are, sweetie.
I have been looking all over for you.
No, not -- not real.
- Not real. - ‭Put that down.
You'll cut yourself.
Are you getting enough to eat here?
I see you're making some friends.
I don't know if I'd call them friends.
You like them. I can tell.
S-Some, maybe.
And that Daisy girl is cute.
Mom, no, she's not.
Stop it.
Remember, sweetie,
the steps you take don't need to be big.
They just need to take you in the right direction.
You always used to say that.
And my mom said it to me.
So, what are you saying? Are you saying that I...
You should walk away.
You know what happens when you care about someone.
No!
- Deke? - ‭No.
You okay?
You look like you've had a fright.
I just saw...another one of those fear things.
I need a Zima.
You shouldn't be alone.
Come back to control. Fitz didn't mean --
Fitz thinks I'm an idiot,
like I don't know up from down.
Well, tell him I'm sorry that I was born in a place
that doesn't have oceans or air or -- or --
You know, and, technically,
there is no up and down in space.
It's all the same thing.
So you can tell him to take all that
science mumbo jumbo and shove it up --
Wait.
It's all the same thing.
You need to look up in the sky.
Our ships float and sink -- they don't fly.
I'm sorry, Deke,
but those are spaceships.
But what if the ship can fly?
It was carrying Gravitonium during a storm.
If it got hit by lightning...
Could have charged the Gravitonium.
And generated a gravity field around the entire ship.
Okay, well, if it was up in the atmosphere,
it would have been tossed about by air currents all these years.
It could be anywhere.
Yeah, so we need to analyze
wind and weather patterns, air currents,
starting from the night it disappeared
and try and build a workable algorithm.
Yeah. That. Let's do all that.
Anything?
Yeah. More clouds.
We're looking ‭for a needle in a haystack.
Or a flying boat.
You got to be kidding me.
Holy moly!
You guys see stuff like this all the time?
- Pretty much. - Yeah. - Yep.
No!
No, get aw-- get away!
I heard screaming.
I don't just remember words and facts.
I remember pain --
every beating I've ever taken,
like it's new.
Over and over.
Well, that...
has got to suck.
I never knew my father.
But my mother --
she's a tyrant.
Keeps me locked up here,
makes me do things that I don't want to do.
She's using me to get to you.
Everything I did -- ignoring you,
letting you touch me,
taking me hostage --
that was all planned,
the grand seduction of Werner von Strucker.
Gain his trust by any means necessary.
You made the right decision.
She doesn't care about you or me --
she only wants what's in your head.
But whatever she's planning, it's not gonna be any different
than Hydra or S.H.I.E.L.D...
unless...
Unless what?
It doesn't have to be her team.
It could be our team...
only she wouldn't know until it was too late.
I don't want to be part of any team.
I just want to go somewhere far away.
With all of those bad memories?
Maybe the key is to bury them
under newer, happier memories.
If you're not here tomorrow...
I'll understand.
But if you are...
?Davis has us in hover mode.
You sure you don't need me down there?
I need someone on the thing
that's actually supposed to be in the air
in case the bottom drops out on us.
I trust you way more than Davis to fly that crazy rescue.
I hear you and don't disagree.
And don't forget to breathe your oxygen.
Five minutes without it, you'll get really loopy.
Okay, camera's on.
May, Fitz, you reading this?
Copy that. Crystal clear.
Yep, copy that. Looking good.
Got to admit -- it's kind of cool
walking around on a ship 25,000 feet up in the sky.
Fitz, how is this even possible?
When the Gravitonium was supercharged,
most likely by a lightning strike,
created an applied gravity field on the ship.
Same way the Gravity Puck works.
That means there's got to be Gravitonium there somewhere.
Well, Deck 1 is clear.
I think we found the crew.
That looks like severe hypoxia.
Let's keep moving.
We're in the engine room.
Looks like someone's been here before us.
Coulson.
Where's the Gravitonium?
Whoever they were, they didn't go home empty-handed.
What's keeping the ship in the air
if there's no Gravitonium?
It's not possible.
Guys, get down here!
What is it?
Gravitonium.
Not all of it, though.
About the size of a softball.
Must have got separated from the rest.
Okay, well, there might be enough there,
but there's a problem.
Yeah, there's always a problem.
You can't touch it or move it.
It's generating the gravity field
that's keeping you in the air.
We're not gonna leave it here.
Is there a plastic box anywhere?
Yeah, we got something. Why?
Okay, listen to me --
if you can box it up without touching it,
- you might be able to get it off the ship. - "Might"?
You got about 90 seconds before the gravity field dissipates.
After that, real gravity is gonna take over,
and the ship's gonna fall out of the sky.
That should be enough time.
All right.
Hey, Mack Hammer.
Can't touch this.
Now is not the time.
Sorry. Couldn't resist.
Clock's ticking.
Let's go before this floating ship
drops miles into the ocean.
On a mission with the two things I fear most --
drowning and heights.
Oh, make that three things.
What are those things?
One of Hale's flying monkeys.
There's another one!
They've got us flanked!
Mack!
They need to get off that ship.
They don't have much time.
You've got less than a minute.
Get the hell out of that ship.
Working on it.
Mack, run for it!
Go to the module. I'll take care of these guys!
- We got to get out! - We don't have time for this.
Go! I know what I'm doing!
It's Hammer Time.
This is not the Mack I used to know.
I'm on my way.
And I'm bringing a couple of guests.
General Hale.
What is it?
Some of the old Sleeper Mechs recently came back online.
Which ones?
The ones you left on the Principia,
in case anyone found it.
We should have blown it out of the sky when we had a chance.
Yeah, it's too risky.
We don't know enough about the Gravitonium.
It could have responded like a nuclear reactor
and set the ozone on fire.
Well, now someone knows about it. Who?
S.H.I.E.L.D.
You know, I wouldn't have believed it
if I hadn't seen it with my own eyes.
Thanks again for your help, Mr. Caine.
Sorry we had to drag you along.
I-I got to see a flying boat and a robot fight.
Best day ever.
We'll have someone take you home in a Quinjet when you're ready.
Thank you. Thanks a lot.
Good to see you again, Tony.
‭Take care.
Good to see you, too, Mack.
And, hey, about that Deathlok program --
your -- your friends were asking about it, too,
so I'm gonna do some digging, see what else I can find.
Yeah, anything, no matter how small.
You got it.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I don't know who that was.
No need to apologize.
Recovery takes a toll physically and emotionally.
I'm just trying to not lose faith.
We're gonna change things.
That's the spirit.
Oh, I'm just holding onto that thing in case of emergency.
Don't beat yourself up while you're trying to heal.
Go slow.
The steps you take don't need to be big.
They just need to take you in the right direction.
Oh. Can we help you with something?
What's wrong, Deke?
Did you see another ghost from your past?
No, it wasn't a ghost.
I...
I just saw you standing there and, uh...
How are you?
What -- I'm --
I -- And, um -- They're -- They're --
They're back.
That -- That's what I came to tell you.
Great.
What?
Nothing.
Is that a new sweater?
Yo-Yo.
Hey, you're up.
One ball of Gravitonium.
Thank you.
Deke, are you coming, or is this another play day?
Yeah, after you, Grandpa.
I think they're growing on each other.
I just hope there's enough Gravitonium for them to work with.
And I think it's safe to say General Hale has the rest.
I'm starting to think she's more than just an overzealous general.
I think you're right.
Guess what I got you.
I don't know. I'm stumped.
So we're doing those jokes now?
No. No more of that,
or I won't share these with you.
Oh, that's right -- I got you something else.
Arms.
We'll return in a moment.
I thought about what you said.
You're right.
The future's ours.
Then you should see who else we've got.
One of your father's old experiments...
but I don't need to tell you that.
You remember everything.
Nice work.
How did you convince him to stay?
I told him the truth.